<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
<eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
<eadid countrycode="US"></eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper type="filing">Branscomb, Harvie Papers</titleproper>
<titleproper>Finding Aid for the Bennet Harvive Branscomb Papers</titleproper>
<author></author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher>Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books</publisher>
<p><date>1894-1998</date></p>
<address>
<addressline>419 21st Avenue South</addressline>
<addressline>Nashville, TN 37203-2427</addressline>
<addressline>specialcollections@vanderbilt.edu</addressline>
<addressline>URL:
<extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.vanderbilt.edu/speccol/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.library.vanderbilt.edu/speccol/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
</address>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<langmaterial>
<language langcode="eng">English</language>
</langmaterial>
<repository>
<corpname>Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books</corpname>
</repository>
<unittitle>Bennet, Harvive Branscomb</unittitle>
<unitid>MSS.0879</unitid>
<physdesc altrender="whole">
<extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.86 linear feet</extent>
</physdesc>
<unitdate>1894-1998</unitdate>
</did>
<scopecontent>
<p>When Harvie Branscomb (Alabama and Wadham &#39;14) came to Vanderbilt in 1 946 ,it was a small private provincial institution. When he relinquished the Chancellorship in 1963, Vanderbilt was a modern, national university. The day after his election, Harvie wrote to a friend, &#34;Vanderbilt has so far as I can find out,all the problems. It does not have enough money, nor enough room, nor enough buildings.</p>
<p>It has, however, a fine academic tradition.&#34; Later, in retrospect, he wrote, &#34;It is clear that I was so convinced that the time had come to establish a great university in the part of the south where I had grown up, that the difficulties in doing it seemed vague and insubstantial in the bright glare of the influences, values and services which would flow from the kind of institution I dreamed of.&#34; Once installed as Vanderbilt&#39;s fourth Chancellor, Harvie Branscomb never looked back. In the seventeen years of his tenure, Vanderbilt would move into the elite circle of the top 20 universities in the country.</p>
<p>Harvie Branscomb was born in Huntsville, Alabama on Christmas day 1894, the son of Lewis and Nannie Branscomb. His father was a methodist minister. His early memories were dominated by the fixed routine of church life in a community that took for granted the truth of traditional Christianity as it was preached in the churches to which they all belonged. Harvie remembered clearly that his Father&#39;s interests were not so much in an evangelistic approach that would try to make saints of people, but in kindling their interests in social problems and political affairs and moral obligations. Harvie recalls that during his college years, he and his father spent many hours discussing critically what he studied and arguing vigorously about intel1ectuial . interests.</p>
<p>Having been graduated from Birmingham College,</p>
<p>Harvie left for Oxford weeks before the start of the First World War.</p>
<p>In the midst of his studies, Harvie and another Rhodes Scholar, Oliver Carmichael, who preceded him as Chancellor of Vanderbilt, volunteered for Herbert Hoover&#39;s Committee for Relief in Belgium. They were asked to carry a letter from Cardinal Mercier condemning the German invasion out of occupied Belgium. They were stopped and searched at the border, but with ingenuity and luck they were able to take the document through. For this they were later awarded the <emph render="underline">Med a i11e d u Ro i Albert</emph>, <emph render="underline">Med a i11e de La Re i ne</emph> (Belgium).</p>
<p>It was at Oxford the he became more interested in the personality of the historic Jesus. He became intrigued with the features of Judaism and the teachings of Jesus that had a common bond. He wrote two books, <emph render="underline">The Teach i ngs of Jesus</emph> and his dissertation,<emph render="underline">Jesus and the Law of Moses</emph>. He won the Canon Hall Greek Testament Prize, and was awarded a BA in Theology First Class with the verbal congratulations of the examiners.</p>
<p>With his studies at Oxford complete, Harvie returned to the US, served a brief stint in the Army, and joined the faculty of Southern Methodist University to teach New Testament.</p>
 <p>The move to Dallas was important for an special reason. He met and married Margaret Vaughn. Theirs was a charmed meeting of two brilliand minds whose love of humanity, learning and beauty was extraordinary. From this point on, all that Harvie was to be professionally and personally was profoundly shaped by her faithful, delightful, and supportive presence. She died in 1991.</p>
<p>In 1925 at SMU, Harvie demonstrated his fierce support for academic freedom and free expression. It seemed that a young assistant professor, a protege of Harvie Branscomb, was causing a stir in the Methodist hierarchy with his provocative liberal lectures. After the young man was dismissed, Harvie wrote a letter to the local newspaper, disagreeing with the process and its conclusion. No sooner was it published than Harvie was &#34;invited&#34; to leave the institution, in spite of his later appeal to the Board of Trustees. Much later, Harvie wrote, &#34;I hold no honorary degree with more pride than the one conferred on me by SMU some years after these events.&#34;</p>
<p>Following his brief stay at SMU, Harvie moved on to Duke, where he spent 21 years, first as a member of the faculty of the School of Religion, then ad Director of the Libraries, and ultimately as dean of the Divinity School.</p>
<p>In 1941 under sposorship of the Carnegie Corporation he published <emph render="underline">Teachi ng with Books</emph>, demonstrating that libraries were seen primarily as repositories for research materials and were little used in class rooms.</p>
<p>He was decorated by the Brazilian government with the Order of the Southern Cross for his work in reorganizing the National Library of Brazil, while serving as chairman of the American Library Association Mission to Brazil in 1 945 .</p>
<p>When in 1946, Harvie Branscomb came to Vanderbilt, he would spend the next seventeen years building the vision he foresaw, and nourishing the academic tradition. Some astonishing things happened.</p>
 <p>The University became a more diverse institution as students from all parts of the country were drawn to Vanderbilt, and in 1952 the doors were opened to minority students before the other private universities in the south took this step. Full-time student enrollment increased even as test scores and grades continued to rise.</p>
<p>During Chancellor Branscomb&#39;s tenure, the number of full-time faculty had doubled, faculty salaries had almost tripled and more buildings were built than had existed when he arrived. The university&#39;s annual budget had increased by more than 400% and the endowment had increased from $38 million in 1946 to $88 million in 1963.</p>
<p>He rebuilt the Medical School and revitalized the Medical Center, which was teetering on the edge of fiscal solvency. Between 1953 and 1963, the schools of Engineering, Divinity and Law acquired their own buildings. Fifteen new residency halls were built. Vanderbilt became a residential campus for undergraduates, which provided the campus culture that remains one of Vanderbilt&#39;s greatest strengths.</p>
<p>Harvie reasserted his interest in Brazil, opening up a research center that lives on to this day, and is now the intellectual home to some of Vanderbilt&#39;s finest scholars and teachers.</p>
<p>Under his leadership, Vanderbilt was elected to the Association of American Universities, the only member in the South between North Carolina and Texas. An important step was his ability to broaden the base of the Board of Trustees by attracting national figures as well as local leaders. Perhaps most important, was his recruitment of Harold Stirling Vanderbilt to be a part of the University his great-grandfather endowed but never saw. Harold Stirling would become President of the Board and later among the most generous philanthropists in Vanderbilt&#39;s history.</p>
<p>During the tumultuous 1 9 6 0 &#39; s , the James Lawson incident occurred. Lawson was a divinity student who participated vigorously in the civil disobedience of the sit-ins. The question of his expulsion arose. Harvie did not think he should be expelled, and brought the question for decision to the Board of Trustees. He counted on his leadership to persuade the Board not to expell Lawson. The Board did expell him. Later Harvie said he should have acted on the question himself. This experience chagrined him for the rest of his tenure.</p>
<p>Harvie found time to serve his country and higher education nationally. President Truman appointed him the first chairman of the US Advisory Commission for Education Exchange, which he led for four years. He later was named chairman of the Commission on Education and International Affairs of the American Council of Education. He advised the World Bank, the United Nations and other government agencies.</p>
<p>Harvie Branscomb&#39;s biography is a history of education in the 20th century, of its continued growth and lustre. Through his efforts and the fullfilment of his visions, Vanderbilt is no longer content with simply being good - it strives for greatness in everything it does.</p>
<p>Long after his retirement, Harvie Branscomb&#39;s presence in Nashville signified leadership and action.</p>
<p>People in all walks of life continued to seek his advice and social contact. He entertained and went out to social events right up to the time of his quiet peaceful death. About three months into his 104th year, he complained quite seriousle that he was having a harder time remembering names !</p>
<p>Chancellor Branscomb is survived by three sons, Harvie Branscomb, Jran attorney in Corpus Christi , Texas, Doctor Ben Branscomb, distinguished professor of medicine, at the University of Alabama Medical School, Birmingham, Alabama, and Lewis H. Branscomb, emeritus professor of public policy and corporate management at Harvard University and a member of Vanderbilt&#39;s Board of Trustees. He is also survived by nine grandchi1dren and nine great-grandchi1dren.</p>
<p>This strong, determined, scholar, theologian and educator will be sorely missed by his many colleagues world wide and by the numerous people upon whom he has left his rich mark of friendship and wisdom.</p>
<p>F .Tremai ne Bi11ings</p>
<p>(Pennsylvania and Balli o1 &#39;33)</p>
</scopecontent>
<dsc type="othertype">
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Outgoing Correspondence Index</unittitle>
</did>
<note>
<p>Correspondence is listed chronologically. The folder number is indicated by the abbreviation F.</p>
</note>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1929</unitdate>
<unittitle>Feb. 7 to the Rockefeller Foundation; F 1.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1946</unitdate>
<unittitle>Oct. 7 to Bishop Walter Peele; Oct. 29 to Bishop W.W. Peele; Nov. 8 to members of the North Carolina Conference; Nov. 29 to Prof. Albert Outler; Dec. 2 to Bishop W.W. Peele; F 1.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1949</unitdate>
<unittitle>Nov. 7 to James E. Webb; FI.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1950</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 23 to Robert D. Calkins; May 30 to William Waller; Nov. 27 to Earl J. McGrath; F 1.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1960</unitdate>
<unittitle>Nov. 1 to Henry Alexander; F 1.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1961</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 6 to Dr. J. Robert Nelson; Feb. 20 from Mrs. Collier Dawson (Secretary to the Chancellor) to Sam Fleming; Mar. 20 to Henry Alexander; May 29 to Baxter Jackson; June 22 to Harold Vanderbilt; July 4 to Harold Vanderbilt; July 7 to Harold Vanderbilt (typescript copy of July 4 letter); July 30 (copied Aug. 1) to Henry C. Alexander ; Sept. 21 to Prof. Willard Jewell; Sept. 27 to Lillian Dorothy Cates; Nov. 1 to Willard Jewell; Dec. 18 to Willard Jewell; Dec. 18 to Robert Lester; Dec. 20 to Henry Alexander; F 1.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1962</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 29 to Henry C. Alexander; Feb. 20 to Henry Alexander; Mar. 2 to Henry Alexander; Mar. 5 to Henry Alexander; Mar. 9 to Richard C. Rowson; Apr. 26 to Henry Alexander; May 17 to Charles C. Trabue, Jr.; May 21 to Alfred Miller; May 30 to Weldon T. Ellis; Aug. 20 to Dr. J.L. Morrill; Sept. 17 to Richard H. Demuth; Nov. 13 to Richard DeMuth; Nov. 20 to George V. Allen; F 1.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1963</unitdate>
<unittitle>Feb. 25 to Philip H. Coombs; Mar. 20 to J.E. Jonsson; Apr. 10 to Carlisle H. Humelsine; (May 28) to Bob (Nelson); June 28 to Grayson Kirk; July 1 to W. Allen Wallis; July 12 to May Davie (Mrs. Preston); Sept. 27 to Mrs. Preston Davie Nov. 4 to Rodney Jones; Nov. 27 to The Honorable Lucius D. Battle; Nov. 27 to I.L. Jones, Jr.; Nov. 27 to Arthur Minnich; Nov. 27 to Prof. Ewing Shahan; Dec. 19 to The Honorable William Ayres; Dec. 19 to The Honorable Edith Green; Dec. 19 to Senator Gale W. McGee; Dec. 19 to The Honorable Edward R. Murrow; F 1.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1964</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 31 to The Honorable Ellis Arnall; Mar. 18 to Harry Bober; Mar. 18 to Matthew G. Kayuza; Mar. 20 to P.N. Kirpal; Mar. 20 to Eugene M. Schaeffer; Mar. 24 to Dr. Malcumb Adeseshiah; Mar. 24 to Dr. Archibald MacLeish; Mar. 25 to Dr. Luther Terry; Mar. 25 (memo re: travel authorization for U.S. National Commission); Mar. 27 to Dr. Takajiro Inone; Mar. 27 to Senator A. Willis Robertson; Apr. 2 to Mrs. Lee Douglas (Marguerite); Apr. 8 to Dr. Frederick H. Burkhardt; Apr. 8 to Marcus Ginsburg; Apr. 18 to Prof. Walter Harrelson; Apr. 10 to Senator J. Caleb Boggs; Apr. 13 to Senator Gale McGee; Apr. 14 to The Honorable Harlan Cleveland; May 16 to Prof. William S. Dix; May 16 to Olive G. Turner; May 28 to Dr. Eugene H. Jacobson; June 12 to Rudolph Bares, Jr.; June 18 to Dr. Arthur Lawson; June 27 to Edwin Hughes; June 27 to Dr. Harold Spivacke; June 30 to Dr. 0. Meredith Wilson; Sept. 8 to Robert S. Lyle; Sept. 19 to Chancellor Alexander Heard; Sept. 28 to The Honorable Harlan Cleveland; Sept. 28 to The Honorable Harry C. McPherson, Jr.; Sept. 28 to Leonard C. Meeker; Oct. 30 to Malcolm S. Adiseshiah; Oct. 30 to Marcus Ginsburg; Dec. 2 to The Honorable Harry C. McPherson, Jr.; Nov. 13 to The Honorable Wladyslaw Grzedzielski; Nov. 15 to Prof. Athanase Joja; Nov. 17 memorandum to Senator Benton; Nov. 18 memorandum to Senator Benton; Dec. 27 to Veda Prakasha; Dec. 2 to Dr. Luther Terry; n.d. to Alan Pifer; F 1.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1965</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 6 to Dr. Paul J. Braisted; Jan. 7 to Honorable Stefan Wierblowski; Jan. 8 to Dr. Frederick H. Burkhardt; Jan. 8 to Mrs. Lawrence M.C. Smith; Jan. 8 to Dr. Mabel W. Smythe; Jan. 11 to Prof. Athanase Joja; Jan. 24 to Van Alen Holloman; Jan. 27 to Honorable Malcolm S. Adiseshiah; Jan. 29 to Ambassador Adlai E. Stevenson; Feb. 3 to Senator William Fulbright; Feb. 3 to Van Alen Holloman; Mar. 1 to Governor Frank Clement; Mar. 2 to Perrin C. Galpin; Mar. 2 to Grayson Kirk; Mar. 2 to Dr. Agustin Yanez; Mar. 4 to William Platt; Mar. 10 to Grayson Kirk; Mar. 10 to Allen A. Michie; Apr. 1 to Tom Ford; Apr. 2 to The Honorable Samuel J. Cookey; Apr. 5 to The Honorable Dean Rusk; Apr. 6 to Prof. Herbert W. Schneider; Apr. 7 to Senator J.W. Fulbright; Apr. 7 to Lawrence M.C. Smith; Apr. 9 to The Honorable Robert H.B. Wade; Apr. 9 to Dr. James Watt; Apr. 17 to The Honorable Dean Rusk; Apr. 19 to Dr. John H. Fisher; Apr. 19 to The Honorable Arthur W. Hummel, Jr,; Apr. 19 to Prof. Herbert Schneider; Apr. 28 to Robert Stanford; May 28 to Dr. Luther Terry; June 3 to Sidney G. Tickton; June 11 to Senator Ross Bass; June 11 to The Honorable Joe L. Evins; June 11 to Senator Albert Gore; June 11 to Prof. Athanase Joja; June 14 to F. William Beckinsale; July 19 to Robert P. Bass, Jr.; July 19 to Prof. John W. Hall; July 23 to President Lyndon B. Johnson; Aug. 6 to Marilyn Chelstrom; Aug. 6 to Dr. Herbert B. Pahl; Aug. 6 to Dr. S. John Reisman; Aug. 10 to Sidney G. Tickton; Oct. 7 to Ben Brodinsky; Oct. 7 to Dr. A. Hollis Edens; Oct. 7 to Henry L. Wright; Oct. 13 to Prof. Athanase Joja; Oct. 14 to Harold Vanderbilt; Oct. 15 to Eldon Dec. 22 to Clare M. Torrey; Dec. 23 to Dr. William H. Stewart; n.d. to educators re: UNESCO and International Cooperation Year; F 2.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1966</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 26 to Dr. Benjamin D. Blood; June 7 to Oris N. Treadwell; July 5 to Dr. Lawrence A. Kimpton; July 8 to The Honorable Dean Rusk; July 9 to The Honorable William Stewart; Aug. 5 to Arthur Minnich; Aug. 24 to Dr. Andrew G. Wallace; Aug. 24 to Dr. Margaret D. West; Aug. 26 to Mrs. Preston Davie; Aug. 26 to Dr. Margaret West; Sept. 23 to The Honorable Douglas Batson; Oct. 10 re: Johnston College; Oct. 14 to George H. Armacost; Nov. 15 to Honorable Carl B. Hyatt; Dec. 5 to Douglas Batson; Dec. 5 to Honorable Charles Frahkel; F 2.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
<unittitle>Mar. 17 to George H. Armacost; Apr. 13 to Dr. Alvin C. Eurich; Apr. 13 to The Honorable Pardee Lowe; May 25 to Senator Howard A. Baker; May 25 to Mrs. J. Paschall Davis; May 25 to The Honorable Charles Frankel; ay 25 to Senator Gore; June 27 to Alvin C. Eurich; Aug. 5 to Mrs. Dexter 0. Arnold; Aug. 28 to Mrs. Fort Linton; Aug. 29 to Mrs. William Bradley; Aug. 29 to D.F. Gunnells; Aug. 29 to Dr. John H. Harris; Aug. 29 to Prof. F.H. Hazlehurst; Aug. 29 to Thomas Steele; Aug. 29 to Mrs. Willard Tirrill; Aug. 29 to Mrs. Robert White; Sept. 26 to members of the committee on the aims and objectives of Cheekwood; Oct. 30 to Justice Tom Clark; Oct. 30 to Dean Alex Domonkos; Oct. 30 to Dr. Lawrence A. Kimpton; Oct. 30 to Henry F. Lochte; Oct. 30 to Clare M. Torrey; Nov. 9 to The Honorable William B. Stevenson; Nov. 9 to Billy Sumner; Nov. 9 to Clare M. Torrey; Nov. 17 to Dr. William J. Bakrow; Nov. 17 to Justice Tom C. Clark; Nov. 17 to Lawrence A. Kimpton; Nov. 17 to L. Arthur Minnich; Dec. 6 re: UNESCO; F 2.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
<unittitle>Mar. 6 to Judge Carl B. Hyatt; Mar. 18 to Chancellor Peter Sa Martino; May 7 to Judge Carl B. Hyatt; May 27 to Mrs. Preston Davie; Dec. 27 to Willard K. Laughlin; Dec. 27 to Harlan Matthews; F 2.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1970</unitdate>
<unittitle>July 20 to James F. McClellan; F 2.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1972</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 17 to Henry Swint; F 2.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1976</unitdate>
<unittitle>June 21 to Judge C.G. Neese; Nov. 1 to D. Bruce Shine; F 2.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1977</unitdate>
<unittitle>May 18 to Dr. Hardy Liston; F 2.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>1978</unitdate>
<unittitle>Oct. 31 to Prof. Eason; F 2.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
<unittitle>To Rex Moon; to Ambassador Alexei P. Pavlov; to Dr. William H. Stewart; F 2.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Incoming Correspondence Index</unittitle>
</did>
<note>
<p>The correspondence is listed alphabetically. The figure in parentheses immediately following each name indicates the total number of letters from that correspondent in the collection. The full name of the person is given whenever possible. The folder number is listed at the end of each entry preceded by the letter F.</p>
</note>
<index>
<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">A</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Acheson, Dean,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 24, 1949; F 29.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Acheson, Dean,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 24, 1949; F 29.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Adiseshiah, Malcolm S.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Oct. 29, 1964; F 26; Feb. 10, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Alcott, James A.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 8, 1969; F 16.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Allen, George V.,</persname>
<ref>(3); Mar. 17, Apr. 28, 1949; F 29; Nov. 5, 1962; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Allen, Helen A.,</persname>
<ref>(3); Oct. 27, Dec. 15, 1976, Apr. 1, 1977; F 25.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Alexander, Henry C.,</persname>
<ref>(3); Nov. 9, 1960, Feb. 10, 1962, Feb. 20, 1962 (Memorandum with enclosures); F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Alexander, Ridley,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 21, 1967 (also signed by Bill Brock, Richard Fulton, Frank C. Gorrell, Cecil C. Humphreys, Edwin 0. Norris); F 14.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Anderson, Bettina,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 2, 1965; F 13.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Anderson, Donald G,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 4, 1948; F 3.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Anderson, Robert Nelson,</persname>
<ref>(2); June 18, 1968, June 2, 1969; F 19.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Armacost, George H.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Aug. 24, Oct. 17, 1966; F 4.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Arnall, Ellis,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 8, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Atterbury, Boudinot P.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Jan. 23, 1968; F 19.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">B</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bailey, Robert H.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Mar. 1, May 10, 1977; F 25.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bakrow, William J.,</persname>
<ref>(6); Nov. 14, Nov. 20, 1967, Jan. 26, July 30, 1968, May 20, 1969, n.d.; F 18.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bares, Rudolph, Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 4, 1964; F 10.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bass, Robert P., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 27, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Batson, Douglas N.,</persname>
<ref>(6); July 8, 1965, Oct. 26, 1965, Nov. 12, 1965; F 22; Aug. 31, Nov. 17, 1966, Jan. 27, 1967 (addressed to Dr. Thomas F. Malone); F 22.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Batson, Randolph,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 8, 1966 (with enclosure); F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Battle, Lucius D.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Nov. 15, 1963; F 3; June 29, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Baumann, Carol Edler,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 15, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Beckinsale, F. William,</persname>
<ref>(2); May 24, June 3, 1965; F 13.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bellinger, Frederick,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 7, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Benedict, Andrew,</persname>
<ref>(2); Oct. 7, 1946, July 2, 1973; F 33.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Benton, John Keith,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 28, 1953; F 33.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Benton, William,</persname>
<ref>(2); Nov. 18, 1964; F 21; Oct. 25, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Berve, Nancy M.</persname>
<ref>(2); Jan. 20, Jan. 23, 1969 (addressed to Rexford G. Moon, Jr. F 4.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Betancour-Mejia, Gabriel,</persname>
<ref>(1); Jan. 17, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bigwood, E.J.,</persname>
<ref>(2); May 8, 1965 (addressed to friends and alumni of BAEF), July 18, 1965 (addressed to Sidney A. Mitchell); F 9</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname>Binns, Josephine,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 4, 1967; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bitker, Bruno V.,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 14, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bing, Peter S.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 15, 1965; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Blood, Benjamin D.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Jan. 19, Mar. 15, 1966; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bober, Harry,</persname>
<ref>(7); June 2, 1964, Dec. 6, 1965, Mar. 22, Apr. 4, July 20, Aug. 26, 1966, Apr. 1969 (addressed to members); F 9.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Boggs, J. Caleb,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 15, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bogue, E. Grady,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 5, 1977 (addressed to Dr. Paul Sands); F 24.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bolden, Wiley S.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Aug. 29, 1969; F 4.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bradley, Mrs. W.T.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 12, 1967; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bragg, John T.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 6, 1967 (statement to the Joint Committee on Constitutional Revision of the 85th General Assembly); F 14.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Braisted, Paul J.,</persname>
<ref>(6); Nov. 14, 1963 (addressed to M. Rene Maheu), Dec. 31, 1963, July 1, Dec. 10, 1964; F 21; Aug. 16, Sept. 16, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Brock, Joseph H.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 6, 1962; F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Brodinsky, Ben,</persname>
<ref>(2); Apr. 27, Oct. 2, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Brown, Wayne,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 7, 1977; F 24.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bryan, E.D.,</persname>
<ref>(5); July 13, 1965 (addressed to Michael Rapuano), July 13, 1965 (addressed to E.S. Gardner), July 13, 1965 (addressed to William Platt), July 15, 1965 (addressed to Arch Boone), Aug. 9, 1965 (addressed to E.C. Roberts); F 35.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Butterfield, Victor,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 19, 1966; F 6.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Byrd, Benjamin F., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Aug. 1, 1973; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">C</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Cale, Edgar B.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 22, 1969; F 18.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Carmichael, Mike,</persname>
<ref>(1); Jan. 3, 1950; F 33.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Carson, Van,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 24, 1970 (addressed to Alfred E. Thomas); F 18.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Cates, Lillian Dorothy,</persname>
<ref>(3); Sept. 22, Sept. 29, Oct. 3, 1961; F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Champion, George,</persname>
<ref>(2); Feb. 14, 1961 (addressed to Sam M. Fleming), Mar. 3, 1961 (addressed to Sam M. Fleming); F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Chatenay, L. Peter,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 27, 1962; F 35.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Chelstrom, Marilyn,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 30, 1965; F 21.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Chiappetta, Michael,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 30, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Cikins, Warren I.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Aug. 20, 1969; F 19.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Clark, Tom C.,</persname>
<ref>(7); June 10, 1966 (addressed to Executive Officers), June 10, 1966 (addressed to the Mayor), June 13, Nov. 9, Nov. 13, 1967, May 21, 1969, n.d.; F 19.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Clement, Frank G.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Nov. 8, 1963, Dec. 30, 1964 (memorandum addressed to members of the Board of Trust of the Cordell Hull Foundation); F 12.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Cleveland, Harlan,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 29, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Cole, Jim,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 29, 1968 (addressed to Rexford G. Moon, Jr.); F 4.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Colligan, Francis J.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 30, 1950; F 29.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Connor, Thomas K.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Dec. 1, 1969, Jan. 9, 1970; F 6.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Cooky, S.J.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 23, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Cox, Charles H.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 24, 1967; F 19.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Crawford, Nancy,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 25, 1968; F 14.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">D</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Davie, May,</persname>
<ref>(8); Sept. 2, 1966, Apr. 27, Oct. 18, Nov. 10, 1967, Apr. 29, May 13, 1968, May 2, 1969, June 1, 1973; F 21.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Davis, Mrs. J. Paschall,</persname>
<ref>(3); May 29, 1968, May 21, 1969, May 11, 197(?); F 20.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Davis, W.L.,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 28, 1962; F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Dempsey, Edward W.;</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 7, 1964 (addressed to Dr. Luther Terry); F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Demuth, Richard H.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Sept. 6, 1962, Oct. 31, 1963; F 35.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Dix, William S.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Sept. 16, 1963, Apr. 23, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Dolley, Robert D.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 20, 1965 (addressed to Thomas Ford); F 13.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Dvorak, Raymond F.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 7, 1972; F 15.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">E</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Eason, Douglas 0.,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 30, 1979; F 24.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Edens, A. Hollis,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 8, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Elliott, Charles, Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 25, 1965; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Elliott, William Y.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Jan. 30, 1961 (addressed to Kenneth Holland), Feb. 7, 1961; F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Ellis, Weldon T.,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 24, 1962; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Eurich, Alvin C.,</persname>
<ref>(9); Feb. 7, 1966, Apr. 10, June 22, 1967, Jan. 24, Sept. 18, Sept. 25, Nov. 7, Dec. 17, 1968, Sept. 25, 1969, Mar. 12, 1975; F 4.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Everton, John Scott,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 15, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">F</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Fisher, John Hurt,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 26, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Fleming, Sam M.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Feb. 17, Mar. 6, 1961; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Frankel, Charles,</persname>
<ref>(2); May 23, May 31, 1967; F 22.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Fulbright, J.W.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Feb. 8, Apr. 26, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">G</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Gallinger, William D.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 20, 1969; F 18.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Galloway, C.B.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 17, 1972; F 15.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Galpin, Perrin C.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Feb. 1, 1965 (addressed to members); Jan. 16, 1966, Jan. 16, 1966; F 9.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Garner, R.L.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Nov. 7, 1960, Aug. 11, 1961 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander); F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Garnsey, Morris E.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Jan. 5, 1967; F 9.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Gehrig, Leo D.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 21, 1966; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Gerbner, George,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 1, 1965 (addressed to Lawrence M.C. Smith); F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Ginsberg, Marcus,</persname>
<ref>(3); Apr. 6, Oct. 28, 1964, n.d.; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Gore, Albert,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 25, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Green, Edith,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 12, 1963; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Grisham, Frank P.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 14, 1977; F 33.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Grundfest, Jerry,</persname>
<ref>(1); Jan. 13, 1976; F 15.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Grzedzielski, Wladyslaw,</persname>
<ref>(1); (Christmas card, 1965); F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Gunnells, D.F.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 1, 1967; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Gwinn, Robert L.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 18, 1969 (addressed to Billy T. Sumner); F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>


<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">H</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hagel, Raymond <emph render="italic">C.,</emph></persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 23, 1969; F 16.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Harari, Maurice,</persname>
<ref>(2); Apr. 15, Apr. 20, 1965 (enclosed copy of report on Mission to India - Mar. 12-28, 1965); F 13.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hardie, Frances,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 26, 1975; F 33.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Haussamen, Crane,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 26, 1964 (Airgram addressed to Dept, of State); F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hays, Brooks,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 7, 1969, Dec. 17, 1969, n.d.; F 19.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hazlehurst, F. Hamilton,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 21, 1967; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Heard, Alexander,</persname>
<ref>(5); Mar. 2, 1964 (addressed to Mrs. Preston Davie); F 21; Mar. 6, 1965 (addressed to Harold S. Vanderbilt), Mar. 18, 1965 (addressed to Harold S. Vanderbilt); F 35; Nov. 8, 1965 (addressed to Robert K. Carr), Nov. 18, 1965 (memorandum to conmittee on Relationships between the Divinity School and Oberlin College); F 33.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hester, James M.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 1, 1973; F 15.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hicks, Henry D.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 28, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hill, Lister,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 30, 1964; F 7.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hliddal, Freda T.,</persname>
<ref>(4); Sept. 28, Oct. 20, 1970, Oct. 11, Nov. 11, 1973; F 15.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hobson, Jesse E.,</persname>
<ref>(12); June 27, July 2, Aug. 11, Aug. 12, 1969 (addressed to Dr. Joseph F. Volker), Aug. 15, Sept. 5, Nov. 11, 1969, Feb. 9, Feb. 19, Mar. 16, Apr. 3, June 6, 1970; F 16.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hoffman, Paul G.;</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 22, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Houle, Cyril 0.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Jan. 20, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Houston, Frank K.,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 2, 1973; F 33.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hughes, Edwin,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 24, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Humelsine, Carlisle H.,</persname>
<ref>(3); Nov. 25, 1953 (addressed to Mr. Chorley), Apr. 1, 1963; F 6; Jan. 8, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hummel, Arthur W., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 31, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hyatt, Carl B.,</persname>
<ref>(9); Mar. 23, Oct. 19, Nov. 21, 1966, Dec. 14, 1967, May 15, June 21, 1968 (telegram), Oct. 8, 1968, Feb. 19, 1969, Feb. 19, 1969 (addressed to Justice Clark); F 19.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">J</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>James, Pauline,</persname>
<ref>(1); Jan. 13, 1969; F 20.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Jewell, Willard B.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 14, 1961 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander with enclosure); F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Johnson, Lyndon B.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Sept. 8, 1965, n.d.; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Johnson, William C.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 25, 1949; F 29.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Joja, Athanase,</persname>
<ref>(2); Apr. 30, Dec. 1, 1965 (telegram); F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Jones, James A.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 2, 1960; F 34.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Jonsson, J.E.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Mar. 6, Mar. 26, 1963; F 17.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Jordan, Constance,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 27, 1970 (addressed to Bernard Werthan, also signed by Anna M. Wilson); F 31.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Judson, Sheldon,</persname>
<ref>(2); Dec. 16, 1964, Jan. 29, 1965 (addressed to members BAEF - also signed by George Wickes); F 9.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">K</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Karp, Basil,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 27, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Karp, Robert E.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 18, 1967; F 18.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Kelley, Robert W., Sr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 29, 1970; F 31.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Keppel, Francis,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 20, 1963; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Kern, Paul B.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 11, 1946; F 3.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname>Kidd, Charles V.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 12, 1964; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Kimpton, Lawrence A.,</persname>
<ref>(2); June 21, 1966, Nov. 10, 1967; F 21.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>King, Helen S.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Mar. 12, 1965, Dec. 28, 1965; F 9.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Kirk, Grayson,</persname>
<ref>(2); June 24, 1963, Apr. 3, 1965; F 2.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Kissick, William L.,</persname>
<ref>(3); Aug. 18, 1966, Apr. 19, 1967, Sept. 18, 1967; F 25.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Kohn, Clyde F.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 23, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Kotschnig, Walter,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 17, 1964 (addressed to Senator Benton); F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Kubler, George,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 5, 1964 (addressed to L.A. Minnich); F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">L</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Larson, Arthur,</persname>
<ref>(1); Aug. 29, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Laves, Walter H.C.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 22, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Leavitt, Milo David,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 17, 1964; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Leestman, Robert,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 22, 1967; F 22.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Lester, Robert M.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 27, 1961; F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Lewis, Cotesworth P.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 25, 1963; F 10.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Liebaers, Herman,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 21, 1966; F 9.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Livingston, Robert B.,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 11, 1964; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Lowe, Pardee,</persname>
<ref>(2); May 2, May 12, 1967; F 22.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Lyle, Robert S.,</persname>
<ref>(8); May 27, 1963, Mar. 25, Aug. 18, 1964, Jan. 4, Jan. 11, Jan. 26, Feb. 5, 1965; F 17; Apr. 7, 1967; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">M</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>MacArthur, Douglas, II,</persname>
<ref>(2); May 27, 1965 (addressed to Senator Robinson), June 22, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>MacBeth, Russell,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 16, 1970 (addressed to Thomas L. Cummings, Jr.); F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>McClellan, James F.,</persname>
<ref>(2); June 23, 1970, Dec. 3, 1970; F 31.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>McClurry, Forrest,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 14, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>McGaw, Robert A.</persname>
<ref>(1); June 7, 1973; F 33.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>McGee, Gale,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 8, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>McGugin, Dan E., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 30, 1962 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander); F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>MacLeish, Archibald,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 17 (?); F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Macomber, William B., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 1, 1965 (addressed to William W. Marvel); F 13.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>McPherson, Harry C., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(5); Oct. 16, 1964; F 7; Jan. 18, Apr. 12, June 1, Aug. 11, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Macy, John W., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 7, 1965 (addressed to Ellis Arnall); F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Maheu, Rene,</persname>
<ref>(4); (1964, addressed to Paul J. Braisted), July 16, 1964; F 26; Dec. 31, July 15, 1965 (telegram); F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Marvel, William W.,</persname>
<ref>(3); May 13, June 15, 1965, June 15, 1965 (addressed to William B. Macomber, Jr.); F 13.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Mezoff, Earl R.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 10, 1978; F 25.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Miller, Alfred,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 7, 1962; F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Miller, Charles,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 9, 1968; F 31.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Miller, Watson B.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 31, 1949 (addressed to George V. Allen); F 29.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Minnich, L.A.,</persname>
<ref>(12); Dec. 9, 1963, Feb. 27, 1964 (addressed to Archibald MacLeish), Apr. 8, 1964 (addressed to Lawrence M.C. Smith), June 26, 1964, Sept. 29, 1964 (addressed to George Kubler), Nov. 20, 1964 (addressed to Robert H.B. Wade), Dec. 18, 1964; F 26; Jan. 4, 1965 (addressed to Mrs. Lawrence M.G. Smith), Oct. 27, 1965 (addressed to Thomas F. Malone), Jan. 7, 1966 (addressed to Wladyslaw Grzedzielski), Apr. 18, 1966, Nov. 7, 1967; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Mitchell, Sidney A.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 22, 1965 (addressed to Prof. E.J. Bigwood); F 9.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Moon, Rexford G., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(3); Jan. 9, 1969; F 4; Feb. 26, 1969; F 20; Jan. 8, 1970; F 4.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Moses, Robert,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 19, 1973; F 15.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Murdock, Richard C.,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 14, 1965 (addressed to E.E. Bryan); F 35.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">N</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Neese, C.G.,</persname>
<ref>(6); June 10, June 28, Nov. 1, Nov. 15, 1976, Feb. 25, Mar. 8, 1977; F 25.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Nelson, Allan,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 21, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Nelson, J. Robert,</persname>
<ref>(4); Aug. 20, Dec. 25, 1960, May 21, June 6, 1963; F 34.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Nguyen-Dinh-Hoa,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 8, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Nicholson,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 29, 1949; F 29.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Niles, Russell Denison,</persname>
<ref>(9); Nov. 1, 1970, Sept. 17, Dec. 14, 1971, June 9, 1972, June 12, 1973 (telegram), May 31, June 1, June 15, Sept. 14, 1973; F 15.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">P</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Pahl, Herbert B.,</persname>
<ref>(3); July 9, Aug. 4, 1964, Sept. 8, 1965; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Pecson, Geronima T.,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 27, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Peele, W.W.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 11, 1946; F 3.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Perinbam, Lewis,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 4, 1964 (addressed to L.A. Minnich); F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Phillips, Richard I.,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 18, 1966; F 22.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Platt, William,</persname>
<ref>(2); Sept. 4, 1964, Feb. 5, 1965; F 35.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Powell, Lewis,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 22, 1965; F 10.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Prakasha, Veda,</persname>
<ref>(2); Oct. 13, Oct. 17, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Price, Charles C.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 10, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Price, Don,</persname>
<ref>(3); Dec. 20, 1961, Feb. 4, 1962 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander), Feb. 17, 1962 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander); F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">Q</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Ouarterman, Elsie,</persname>
<ref>(1); Aug. 17, 1967; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Quero-Chiesa, Luis,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 13, 1967; F 15.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">R</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Reams, Elinor P.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Mar. 17, 1949 (addressed to Mr. Linton), Nov. 1, 1950; F 29.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Reisman, S. John,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 18, 1964; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Riddle, Rebecca,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 2, 1967; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Robertson, Cathy,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 1, 1966 (addressed to Mary Irvine); F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Rosenfeld, Barbara,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 12, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Rowson, Richard C.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 28, 1962; F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Rusk, Dean,</persname>
<ref>(3); Jan. 26, Apr. 27, 1965, Dec. 18, 1967; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">S</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Sands, Paul,</persname>
<ref>(1); Aug. 29, 1977; F 24.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Sargent, Howland H.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 19, 1948; F 29.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 2, 1963; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Schwenkmeyer, Barry,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 2, 1968; F 4.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Scott, Gordon,</persname>
<ref>(2); Mar. 8, 1965, July 23, 1967; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Seidman, P.K.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 8, 1968; F 14.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Shannon, James A.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Sept. 17, 1965, Jan. 4, 1966; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Sharp, Walter,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 15, 1965 (addressed to R.D. Stanford, Jr.); F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Shayne, May W.,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 30, 1977; F 3.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Shine, D. Bruce,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 28, 1976; F 25.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Shulman, Herbert L.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Aug. 9, 1976; F 25.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Shuster, George N.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 18, 1963; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Silberman, Lou H.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 16, 1960; F 34.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Sisco, Joseph J.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Aug. 18, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Sockman, Ralph W.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Oct. 26, 1964, June 1, 1970; F 15.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Smith, Lawrence M.C.,</persname>
<ref>(3); May 12, 1964; F 26; Mar. 25, 1965 (addressed to to Harry C. McPherson), June 18, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Smith, William S.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 1, 1968; F 31.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Smythe, Mrs. Hugh H.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 26, 1964 (addressed to Robert H.B. Wade); F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Spivacke, Harold,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 2, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Starabaugh, John H.,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 30, 1962 (addressed to Harold Vanderbilt); F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Stanford, R.D.,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 5, 1965; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Steele, Thomas Wardlaw,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 5, 1967; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Stevenson, Eldon, Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 19, 1971 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander); F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Stevenson, William E.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Oct. 20, Nov. 17, 1967; F 6.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Stewart, Ella Phillips,</persname>
<ref>(1); Aug. 9, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Stewart, William H.,</persname>
<ref>(4); Jan. 24, June 27, Oct. 7, 1966, Sept. 8, 1967; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Sumner, Billy T.,</persname>
<ref>(6); June 24, Sept. 21, 1967, Nov. 21, 1967 (telegram), Nov. 27, 1967, May 28, 1968 (addressed to Neil Bass, Robert L. Gwinn, Robert Street, Charles Waterfield, with copy of May 14, 1968 letter to Sumner), Apr. 16, 1969 (addressed to Thomas Cunmings, Jr.); F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">T</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Tax, Sol,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 3, 1964 (addressed to Lawrence M.C. Smith); F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Terry, Luther,</persname>
<ref>(4); Jan. 27, Feb. 3, 1964; F 25; June 4, 1965; F 37; July 1, July 30, 1965; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Tickton, Sidney G.,</persname>
<ref>(3); Apr. 13, 1964, Mar. 15, 1965, Aug. 3, 1965; F 4.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Tirrill, Bess B.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 14, 1967; F 23.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Torrey, Clare M.,</persname>
<ref>(7); Mar. 24, Dec. 17, 1964, Jan. 13, Dec. 15, Dec. 28, Jan. 13, 1965, Nov. 3, 1967; F 9.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Trabue, Charles C., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(2); May 10, 1962 (addressed to Harold S. Vanderbilt), June 22, 1962; F 32.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Treadway, Cleo,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 1, 1977; F 25.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Tuck, W. Hallam,</persname>
<ref>(1); Jan. 29, 1965; F 9.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Turner, H. Chandlee, Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 20, 1965; F 10.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Turner, Olive G.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 25, 1964; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">V</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Van Alen Holloman,</persname>
<ref>(2); Sept. 16, 1964, Jan. 27, 1965; F 17.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Vanderbilt, Harold S.,</persname>
<ref>(5); July 31, 1961, June 18, 1962; F 32; Mar. 10, 1965 (addressed to Alexander Heard), Mar. 22, 1965 (addressed to Alexander Heard), Sept. 10, 1965 (addressed to Alexander Heard); F 35.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Van der Eycken, Henri,</persname>
<ref>(3); July 28, 1965 (addressed to Harry Bober); July 28, 1965 (addressed to Clare M. Torrey), Nov. 9, 1965 (addressed to Clare M. Torrey); F 9.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Voss, Thomas G.,</persname>
<ref>(6); Sept. 6, Sept. 20, Dec. 28, 1976, Apr. 22, Oct. 12, 1977, May 17, 1978; F 25.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">W</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Wade, Robert H.B.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Jan. 6, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Walker, Charles R.,</persname>
<ref>(3); Sept. 27, 1968, July 11, Nov. 3, 1969; F 31.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Waller, William,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 23, 1950; F 33.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Walsh, George J.,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 13, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>West, Margaret D.,</persname>
<ref>(3); Apr. 26, Sept. 21, 1966, Feb. 24, 1967; F 30.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Williams, Clanton W.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 16, 1965; F 13.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Williams, M.D.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 10, 1969; F 31.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Wilson, Logan,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 10, 1963; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Wilson, 0. Meredith,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 20, 1963; F 26.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Woods, George D.,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 9, 1963; F 36.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Wright, Henry L.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 23, 1965; F 27.</ref>
</indexentry>

<indexentry>
<persname><emph render="bold">Y</emph></persname>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Young, Dora E.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 13, 1948; F 3.</ref>
</indexentry>
</index>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>1</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">1-2</container>
<unittitle>Correspondence - Outgoing. Feb. 7, 1929 - Oct. 31, 1978. Outgoing correspondence arranged chronologically by year, month and day. Letters are holograph, typescript, printed, photocopies and carbon copies. Includes memoranda. There are 4 undated letters. See Outgoing Correspondence Index.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>1</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Correspondence - Incoming (Miscellaneous). 6 holograph and typescript letters pertaining to various subjects. (All other incoming correspondence is filed according to appropriate subject, but listed alphabetically by author. See Incoming Correspondence Index).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>1</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Academy for Educational Development</emph>. Correspondence.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>5</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Reports and agendas: <emph render="underline">Advisory Committee on the Consortium of Universities of the Washington Metropolitan Area</emph>, July 17, 1968; <emph render="underline">Coordinating Council for Higher Education</emph>, Resolution; <emph render="underline">Detroit Institute of Technology-Today, Tomorrow, and in the Generation Ahead</emph>; <emph render="underline">Educational Trends in Certain Professional Schools in the State of Pennsylvania</emph>; <emph render="underline">Innovations in Undergraduate Education</emph>; <emph render="underline">Major Issues to be Faced in Planning the Future of Higher Education</emph>; <emph render="underline">Faculty Development at Tuskegee Institute</emph>; <emph render="underline">A New Approach to Undergraduate Education</emph>; <emph render="underline">Program of Study of the International University for Independent Study</emph>; <emph render="underline">Proposed Establishment of the International University for Independent Study</emph>; <emph render="underline">A Proposed Program for Undergraduate Instruction</emph>; Recommendations; Summary of Staff Findings and Recommendations regarding the <emph render="underline">Structure and Governance of Higher Education</emph>; University of Redlands report. Newspaper clippings.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>1</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">American Association of Colleges Conference on the Humanities</emph>. Correspondence.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>1</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">American Committee to Preserve Abu Simbel</emph>. Correspondence, lists of committee.members.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>1</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">American Council on Education</emph>. Reports: <emph render="underline">Commission on Education and International Affairs; Conference on the Cultural Relations of the United States and the Soviet Union.</emph></unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>1</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Belgian-American Educational Foundation</emph>. Correspondence. American Association of C.R.B. Alumni, Inc.: Press release, amended complaint. Historical summary. Lists of members and directors. President&#39;s report on lawsuit brought by George Wickes and S. Sheldon Judson, Jr. Newspaper clippings.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>1</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Colonial Williamsburg</emph>. Correspondence. Printed raaterials-brochure, broadsides, map. Board of Trust minutes, lists of trustees and directors.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>1</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Commission on the Humanities of the ACLS</emph>. List of participants in the Worcester Conference. Reports: <emph render="underline">The Graduate School Today and Tomorrow</emph>. <emph render="underline">The Place of Teaching in the Humanities.</emph></unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>1</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">12</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Cordell Hull Foundation for International Education</emph>. Correspondence. Ballot, contract proposal, and financial statements.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>1</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">13</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Education and World Affairs</emph>. Correspondence. Reports: Report on Mission to India, March 12-28, 1965. Report on Summer Institute Follow-Up Program. Trip itinerary, holograph notes. &#34;International Education Act of 1966&#34; bill.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">14</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Foundation for Better Government for Tennessee</emph>. Correspondence. Reports: Board of Trust meeting, resolution. Summary of proposals to amend the Constitution of Tennessee. Lists of members of committee.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">15</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Hall of Fame for Great Americans</emph>. Correspondence. Lists of members, agenda, resolution, rules, minutes of board meeting.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">16</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Heald. Hobson and Associates, Incorporated</emph>. Correspondence. Agendas, lists of advisors.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">17</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Hockaday School</emph>. Correspondence. Lists of board members.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">18</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Motorola Executive Institute</emph>. Correspondence. Reports, list of library books, clippings and holograph notes.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speeches and Papers: Introductions, final words to graduates and memorial resolutions (Vanderbilt University) - Box 5, Folder 38.</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Introductions:</emph></unittitle>
</did>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of Lord Halifax to Duke University audience, ca. 1940.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of Dr. Mims, Neely Auditorium, Jan. 1948.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of John Foster Dulles, June 4, 1950.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of Arthur Hays Sulzberger as conmencement speaker, (1950).</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of David Kaser, Nashville Rotary Club, Dec. 5, 1961.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of Charles Frankel, Friends of the Library dinner meeting, 1978.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Undated:</emph></unittitle>
</did>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of the Very Reverend George M. Alexander.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of O.C. Carmichael, President&#39;s Commission on Higher Education.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of Don R. Elliott, Rotary Club.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of Andy Holt, Rotary Club.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of Dr. Virgil Melvin Hancher of the University of Iowa.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of Major General Jen Lin Huang, Class of &#39;22.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of Dr. Edward McCready.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of Dr. John S. Millis, Nurshing School Anniversary dinner meeting.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Introduction of Randall Stewart as commencement speaker.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Final remarks to graduating class:</emph></unittitle>
</did>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Commencement, 1950.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Commencement, June 8, 1952.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Commencement, 1959.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Comnencement, 1960.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Commencement, June 4, 1961.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Most of you are now leaving academic halls...&#34;, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;It is a tradition of this University that before you leave this campus..,&#34; n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;It is a tradition of this University that before you leave, the Chancellor has the privilege..,&#34; n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;It is a long established custom.n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Final Word,&#34; n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;To Graduates,&#34; n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;No Signs on the Highway,&#34; Baccalaureate Address, May 1973.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Memorial Resolutions:</emph></unittitle>
</did>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>John Keith Benton (1896-1956). Tributes by the Divinity School Faculty and the Chancellor of the University at a memorial service held in Stockham Memorial Chapel, Nov. 28, 1956.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks made at memorial service for Sam Clark, July 3, 1960.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Board of Trust memorial resulution honoring Orrin Henry Ingram, May 4, 1963.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks made at funeral service for Harold S. Vanderbilt, Trinity Episcopal Church, Newport, Rhode Island, July 7, 1970.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Board of Trust memorial resolution honoring Harold Stirling Vanderbilt, 1970.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Board of Trust memorial resolution honoring Nathaniel Baxter Johnson, Nov. 9, 1973.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Board of Trust memorial resolution honoring Robert Livington Garner.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Resolution in memory of Oliver Cromwell Carmichael, Jr., Oct. 22, 1976.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">19</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">National Conference on Citizenship</emph>&#171; Correspondence. Reports, agendas, lists of members. Articles establishing the <emph render="underline">National Citizenship Clubs</emph>. By-laws. Definition of citizenship. Summary of meeting. Summary of Youth Program.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">20</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Planned Parenthood Association of Nashville</emph>. Correspondence. Reports, lists of members. By-laws, minutes of Board Directors&#39; Meeting.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">21</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Robert A. Taft Institute of Government</emph>. Correspondence. Report, printed invitation.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">22</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">State, Department of</emph>. Correspondence.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">23</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Tennessee Botanical Gardens and Fine Arts Center</emph>. Correspondence, lists of board members, reports on aims and objectives.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">24</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Tennessee Higher Education Commission</emph>. Correspondence. Paper on &#34;The Competent College Student.&#34;</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>2</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">25</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Tusculum College</emph>. Correspondence. Lists of board members. Reports: <emph render="underline">The Academic Scene at Tusculum</emph>. Report of the Governance Committee on the <emph render="underline">Future of Academic Programs at Tusculum College Statement of Purpose</emph>, 1977.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>3</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">26</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">UNESCO, 1963-64</emph>. Correspondence. Reports, agendas, lists, notes and printed materials: Printed messages from the President of the United States; membership rosters, papers on <emph render="underline">Freedom of Expression in the Arts</emph>; Report on U.S. National Commission, Financial and Staff Resources; Texts of Human Rights Conventions on Slavery, Forced Labor, Political Rights of Women and Genocide; UNESCO and Education; &#34;Report on UNESCO&#34; by Harvie Branscomb published in <emph render="underline">Bulletin on International Education</emph>; &#34;Progress Report on UNESCO&#34; published in <emph render="underline">Saturday Review</emph>; Report of the U.S. Delegation to the 13th General Conference of UNESCO; Report to the Carnegie Corporation on &#34;The Universities of South and East Africa&#34;; Bangkok Conference of Asian National Commissions; holograph notes; trip itineraries; travel notes on a visit to Asia.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>3</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">27</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">UNESCO, 1964-65</emph>. Correspondence. Reports: <emph render="underline">Some problems related to what extent we emphasize foreign students coming here or sending teachers abroad; Some suggestions for a United States position on the problem of the free flow of information</emph>; <emph render="underline">UNESCO after 20 </emph>Years; Reports of the U.S. Delegation; Recommendations for the UNESCO program; membership lists.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>3</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">28</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">UNESCO, Minutes and Actions</emph>. Reports: <emph render="underline">Soviet Cultural Influence in North Korea</emph>; Objectives; Executive Committee reports on <emph render="underline">Privileges and Immunities Requirement Bars UNESCO-sponsored Meetings in U.S.</emph>,and <emph render="underline">UNESCO and American Universities - Follow-Up Program</emph>.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>3</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">29</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">U.S. Advisory Commission</emph>. Correspondence. Remarks at Seventh Annual Birthday of the Americas Dinner; Trip itineraries; Report on European Trip, Summer 1949.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>3</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">30</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">U.S. Public Health Council</emph>. Correspondence. Reports, agendas, lists and resolutions.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>4</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">31</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Urban League and Race Issues</emph>. Correspondence. Minutes, lists of board members, by-laws, printed materials.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>4</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">32</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Vanderbilt University</emph>. <emph render="underline">Board of Trust Committee on the Succession to the Chancellorship</emph>. Correspondence.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>4</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">33</container>
<unittitle>
<emph render="underline">Vanderbilt University</emph>. <emph render="underline">Documents and Assorted Papers</emph>. Correspondence. Papers, reports, agendas and printed materials.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>4</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">34</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Vanderbilt University</emph>. <emph render="underline">Lawson Affair</emph>. Correspondence. Printed articles: &#34;Is Civil Disobedience the Way?&#34; by Harvie Branscomb, &#34;A Policy the University Can Defend&#34; by Robert McGaw, &#34;Vanderbilt&#39;s Time of Testing&#34; by J. Robert Nelson, &#34;The Lawson- Vanderbilt Affair, Letters to Dean Nelson,&#34; Statement; of Principles and Procedures to be followed in Cases of Student Discipline wherein Issues of Academic Freedom are Raised.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>4</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">34</container>
<unittitle>Reports: Statement made by Harvie Branscomb at the Arts and Science Faculty Meeting on March 8, 1960; Statement made by Dr. Quillian to the Student Body at Assembly on Jan. 3, 1961; Recommendations of the Beach Committee appointed to recommend procedures to be followed in the future; Proposed White Paper on &#34;The Lawson-Nelson Case at Vanderbilt University&#34;; &#34;Some Comments and Reflections on the Lawson Episide.&#34; Newspaper clippings.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>4</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">35</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Vanderbilt University</emph>. <emph render="underline">Statue of Harold S. Vanderbilt</emph>. Correspondence. Papers and printed materials. Photograph.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>4</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">36</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">World Bank Project</emph>. Correspondence. Reports.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<physdesc><extent>4</extent></physdesc>
<container type="folder">37</container>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">World Health Organization</emph>. Correspondence. Reports: Committee on International Health to the National Advisory Health Council; Committee on Progranme and Budget, Provisional Minutes of the Fifteenth Meeting; Draft Sixth Report of the Committee on Programme and Budget; Extension of WHO Activities-Research; Health Aspects of World Population; Some Questions and Comments Concerning the Program of the WHO More Particularly in the Field of Education and Training. Holograph notes, lists of members, travel authorizations.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Draft of Board of Trust memorial resolution honoring Gertrude Conaway Vanderbilt, 1978.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Board of Trust memorial resolution honoring William Oscar Jenkins. Remarks made at memorial service for Charles Robinson.</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speeches and Papers: Vanderbilt University - Box 5, Folder 39.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address to Vanderbilt Alumni, Fall 1946.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Founder&#39;s Day Speech, May 27, 1948.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Honors Day Speech, May 3, 1950.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks to the Nashville Soliciting Team, McTyeire Hall, Sept. 6, 1950.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The State of the University.&#34; Report of the Chancellor to the Alumni, Sept. 1, 1950.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Seventy-fifth Anniversary speech, Oct. 21, 1950.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;State of the University.&#34; Sept. 18, 1951.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at New York luncheon honoring Grantland Rice, Nov. 1, 1956.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at the Fugitives&#39;Reunion, (1956).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at Alumni luncheon, 1957.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Welcome address at Medical School Symposium, 1958 or 1959.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Statements made by Chancellor Branscorab in presenting Board of Trust citations, Oct. 17, 1959.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks at the Dedication of the W.R. Wills Center for Psychiatric Treatment and Research, Jan. 6, 1961.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speech at Veterans Administration Hospital Cornerstone Laying Ceremony,: June 19, 1961.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Welcome to new students, Sept. 13, 1961.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speech to the Faculties, Sept. 15, 1961.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address to the Vanderbilt AAUP, Oct. 2, 1961.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Final speech to the Faculties, Sept. 14, 1962.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speech to the Living Endowment Area Chairmen, Vanderbilt University, Nov. 16, 1962.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks by Dr. Branscorab at dinner, Feb. 7, 1963, given by Mr. and Mrs.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Harold Vanderbilt honoring Mr. and Mrs. Alexander Heard.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Working notes on the contributions of Harold S. Vanderbilt during the period, 1946-63.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;A Janus View,&#34; <emph render="underline">Vanderbilt Alumnus</emph>.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;UNESCO after 20 Years.&#34; Forum, Vanderbilt University, March 31, 1966.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks on the occasion of the Reunion of the Vanderbilt Family at Vanderbilt University, March 17, 1973.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks at Dedication of Bust of Eldon Stevenson, May 4, 1973.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Suggested remarks submitted to Mr. Sam Fleming, re: installation of Dr. TeSelle as Dean of the Divinity School, August 13, 1975.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at program honoring Bill Darby, Nov. 1979.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;O.C. Carmichael, The Man and the Citizen.&#34; Speech for Unveiling Carmichael Portrait, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>General Hospital Proposal (incomplete draft), n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speech for Vanderbilt American Assembly, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks at dedication of Divinity School building and introduction of Liston Pope.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks at the Dedication of the A.B. Learned Graduate Science Hall, Vanderbilt University, Nov. 10.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Chance Remarks.&#34; <emph render="underline">Hustler</emph>.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks at dinner for President Stuntz on his retirement, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks at Rotary dinner at Vanderbilt for Ambassadors from Latin American countries.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Vanderbilt University - October 1946.&#34; Paper requested by Professor Henry Swint.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Toast to the memory of the Commodore.</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speeches: Nashville area - Box 5, Folder 40.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address before the Rotary Club, Oct. 7, 1946.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address before the Civitan Club, Oct. 15, 1946.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;What the Colleges Contribute to the Economy of Nashville.&#34; Address to the Nashville Chamber of Commerce, revised Dec. 1953.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The essence of Communism...&#34; Article for the Nashville <emph render="underline">Tennessean</emph>, Sept. 20, 1959.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The College and University Library.&#34; West End Methodist, July 27, 1960. Speech at the Centennial Club, April 13, 1961.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speech at Cornerstone Laying Ceremony, Veterans&#39; Administration Hospital, Nashville, Tenn., June 22, 1961.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Common Market.&#34; Rotary Club, Feb. 12, 1962.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Keynote Address, National Security Seminar, War Memorial Auditorium, Nashville, March 12, 1962.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address before the Nashville Rotary Club, April 13, 1964.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speech for the National Bank, Dec. 1964.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Some Observations on International Conferences.&#34; Centennial Club,</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Jan. 25, 1966.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address before the Methodist Women&#39;s Group, Dec. 6, 1965.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address before the Rotary Coub, Nashville, June 13, 1966.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address to the Legislature, April 26, 1967.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>U.N. Workshop, Nashville, Oct. 1967.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at the B&#39;nai B&#39;rith Testimonial dinner, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Teaching as a Career,&#34; n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at Stahlman dinner, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at meeting of Nashville Chamber of Commerce, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address before Rotary Club, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address to the Optimist Club, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address to the Chamber of Coinnerce, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speeches: Commencement (outside institutions) - Box 5, Folder 41.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>David Lipscomb College, June 5, 1950.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>University of Chicago, Dec. 22, 1950.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Western Kentucky State College, June 3, 1954.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>University of Mississippi, May 27, 1956.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Brand&#233;is University, June 6, 1958.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Guardians of Wisdom.&#34; Northwestern, 1958.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Rice Institute, June 3, 1960 (also given at Scarritt, 1961 and University of Tennessee, 1962).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>University of Tennessee, March 17, 1962.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Brooke Hill School, Birmingham, May 31, 1968.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Belmont College, May 28, 1971.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Dynamic Education,&#34; Peabody of Scarritt, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Grounds of Our Hope,&#34; Randolph-Macon College for Women, n.d. Commencement address, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speeches: Academic occasions (outside institutions) - Box 5, Folder 42.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Next Ten Years in Education.&#34; Policies and Problems in Higher Education. Seminar, April 1948.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at University of Chattanooga. Opening convocation, Sept. 28, 1948. Speech on &#34;The Future of College Libraries.&#34; Cambridge, Mass., March 31, 1949. Speech at Scarritt, Nov. 9, 1949.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at inaugeration of President West, Meharry, Oct. 20, 1952.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Peabody Sunday Vesper Series, June 10, 1956.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Honors Day, George State College, May 7, 1958.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;A Two-Way Street should have deliveries at both ends.&#34; Paper presented at annual meeting of the National Association of State Universities,</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>May 4, 1959.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speech at Emory University, Nov. 10, 1960.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Colleges and the Business Community.&#34; Address at Birmingham-Southern College, Dec. 2, 1960.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at Chattanooga University, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at Birmingham-Southern, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Phi Beta Kappa address at Emory University, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks at installation of Dr. Rhodes at Southwestern, n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at Fisk University on establishment of Phi Beta Kappa.</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speeches and Papers: Non-academic occasions (outside Nashville) - Box 6, Folder 43.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Editorial, <emph render="underline">Oxonian</emph>, April 1943.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Cecil Rhodes,&#34; Rio de Janeiro, 1945.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Spiritual Values in Higher Education.&#34; Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, Memphis, Tenn., Dec. 13, 1946.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address before the Tennessee Public School Teachers Association, Jan. 10, 1947.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Mature Higher Education.&#34; Rotary Club of Birmingham, Alabama, Sept. 17, 1947.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address before the Tennessee Society of St. Louis, Jan. 10, 1948.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Discussion on Medical Education, A.M.A., Feb. 9, 1948.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Transcript of Proceedings, National Health Assembly, May 24, 1948.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speech made to National Association of Foreign Students Advisers, Cleveland,</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Ohio, March 29, 1949.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Responsibility of the Individual in the Present Crisis.&#34; Birmingham,</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Alabama, Feb. 14, 1951.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Address at the celebration of the One Hundred and Fiftieth anniversary of the founding of Huntsville, Alabama, Sept. 11, 1955.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>American Council Annual Meeting, Oct. 6, 1955.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Changing Temper.&#34; Iron and Steel Institute, Birmingham, Alabama,</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Oct. 23, 1967.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Critique of Niebuhr&#39;s proposal for the Sealantic Fund, Nov. 16, 1959.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Expansion of Higher Education.&#34; International Association of Universities, Mexico City, Sept. 8, 1960.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speech honoring Bill Elliott at luncheon on his retirement from Harvard University, ca. 1960.</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Speeches, Papers, and Book Reviews: Religious issues - Box 6, Folder 44.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Dramatic Instinct of Early Christianity.&#34; Presidential address delivered at the 31st annual meeting of the National Association of Biblical</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Instructors at Union Theological Seminary, N.Y.C., Dec. 27 and 28, 1940.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Jesus and Judaism.&#34; Lecture at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1942.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Jesus and Judaism.&#34; Lecture at Hebrew Union College, Cincinnati, Nov. 1942.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Paul&#39;s Attitude to the Law.&#34; Cincinnati, 1942.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Church of the Second Century.&#34; Cincinnati, 1942.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>World Conference on Faith and Order, the American Theological Committee.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>The Report of the Committee. <emph render="underline">Christendom</emph>, vol. IX, no. 2, Spring 1944.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Memorial to Frederic Moir Hanes <emph render="underline">North Carolina Medical Journal</emph>, vol. 8, no. 3, March 1947.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Meaning of the New Testament.&#34; The Church of the Air Program, C.B.S., Nov. 16, 1947.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Some Mistakes which Parents Make.&#34; Cole Lecture Week, West End Church, April 16, 1950.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Seeking Faith.&#34; Series of talks on <emph render="underline">Faith in Action</emph>, N.B.C., Oct. 26, 1952.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Our Responsibility as Christians toward World Issues.&#34; Address to the women of St. George&#39;s Episcopal Church, Nashville, Feb. 20, 1962.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Book Reviews</emph>:</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Die Jesusfrage im Neuzeitlichen Judentum Ein Beitrag gur Geschichte der Leben-Jesu-Forschung</emph> by Gosta Lindeskog. 1938.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Book of Revelation</emph> by E.F. Scott.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Search for the Real Jesus: A Century of Historical Study</emph> by C.C. McCown.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Understanding the Parables of Our Lord</emph>, by Albert E. Barnett.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Nature and Purpose of the Gospels</emph>, by R.V.G. Tasker.</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Clippings: Vanderbilt University, 1946-1963 - Box 6, Folder 45.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;New Chancellor,&#34; <emph render="underline">Nashville Tennessean</emph>, Aug. 3, 1946.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Holder, Bill. &#34;Portrait of a Chancellor.&#34; Reprinted from the <emph render="underline">Nashville Tennessean Magazine</emph>, Sept. 29, 1946.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Russell, Fred, &#34;The Chancellor Visits Practice.&#34; Oct. 10, 1946.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Chancellor Branscomb-Man for the Job.&#34; <emph render="underline">Nashville Banner</emph>. (1946).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Chancellor Cites Vanderbilt&#39;s Important Role in the South.&#34; <emph render="underline">Nashville Banner</emph>. Aug. 3 (1946).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Installation Proceedings at the Inauguration of Harvie Branscomb as Fourth Chancellor of Vanderbilt University</emph>, Feb. 4, 1947.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Program of Inauguration of Bennett Harvie Branscomb as Fourth Chancellor of Vanderbilt University, Feb. 4, 1947.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Remarks of Frank C. Rand, President Board of Trust at the Inauguration of Bennett Harvie Branscomb as Chancellor of Vanderbilt University, Feb. 4, 1947.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;VU to Inaugurate Branscomb Feb. 4.&#34; (1946).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;VU Chancellor to be Installed.&#34; (1946).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Program for The Newcomen Society in North America at Nashville on March 16th, 1950. Branscomb, Harvie. &#34;Be Yourselves<emph render="super">1</emph>.&#34; <emph render="underline">Listen</emph>, 1954.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Branscomb, Harvie. &#34;Juror Finds His Duty &#39;Refreshing.<emph render="super">1</emph>&#34; July 2, 1957.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Graves, John Temple. &#34;Praised With a Loud Damn.&#34; <emph render="underline">Farmville, VA. Herald</emph>. Dec. 13, 1960.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Christie, Amos. &#34;Some Notes About Vanderbilt in the Old Days.&#34;</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Vanderbilt Alumnus</emph>. July/August 1969.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Wilson, Owen H. &#34;Early History of Medical Education in Nashville.&#34; Reprinted from <emph render="underline">Journal of the Tennessee Medical Association</emph>, Vol. 62, no. 9, Sept. 1969, pp. 819-829.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Reverence and Gratitude,&#34; n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Nashvillians Attend Party in New York,&#34; n.d.</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Clippings: Personal (Post-retirement) - Box 6, Folder 46.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Barker, George. &#34;He Put the Cap on &#39;Dynamite ! &#39; &#34; <emph render="underline">Nashville Tennessean Magazine</emph>, Jan. 8, 1961.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Branscomb Testimonial Issue.&#34; <emph render="underline">Vanderbilt Hustler</emph>. Jan. 11, 1963.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Branscomb, Harvie. &#34;V.U. Alumni in Taiwan, Prosperity in Hong Kong.&#34; <emph render="underline">(Nashville Banner</emph>, 1964).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Branscomb, Harvie. &#34;Incisive Analysis of Communist Technique.&#34; <emph render="underline">(Nashville Banner</emph>, 1964).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Branscanb, Harvie. &#34;The Vastness of India, Complexity of Aid Plans.&#34; <emph render="underline">(Nashville Banner</emph>, 1964).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Branscomb, Harvie. &#34;Egypt: Mixture of Grandeur, Problems.&#34; (<emph render="underline">Nashville Banner</emph>, 1964).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Branscomb, Harvie. &#34;Hard Working Japan Is Dependable U.S. Ally.&#34; <emph render="underline">(Nashville Banner</emph>, 1964).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Branscomb, Harvie. &#34;V.U. Alumni in Taiwan, Prosperity in Hong Kong.&#34; <emph render="underline">(Nashville Banner</emph>, 1964).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Dodson, Anne. &#34;Multi-Nation Pact Reached By Diplomacy.&#34; <emph render="underline">Corpus Christi Caller</emph>. Dec. 14, 1965.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;World Bank Officer Praises Dr. Branscomb.&#34; <emph render="underline">Nashville Banner</emph>, Feb. 14, 1967. Branscomb, Harvie. &#34;Teaching with Books.&#34; June, 1973.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Branscomb.&#34; <emph render="underline">Vanderbilt Hustler</emph>. Oct. 27, 1978.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Fine, Benjamin. &#34;Free Interchange of Culture Urged.&#34;</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Printed materials - Box 6.</unittitle>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">The American Oxonian.</emph> &#34;Oliver Cromwell Carmichael (1891-1966),&#34; pp. 48-50.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Baptist Student</emph>. &#34;UNESCO, World Market for Ideas,&#34; pp. 6-9.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Competent College Student. An Essay on the Objectives and Quality of Higher Education</emph>. Discussion paper sponsored by the Tennessee Higher Education Commission and funded by a grant from the Ford Foundation, April 1977.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;The Contribution of Moral and Spiritual Ideas to the Making of the American Way of Life.&#34; Lecture delivered at the University of Wisconsin, March 19, 1952.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>The Duke Divinity School Bulletin. Vol. 3, #3, Nov. 1942. &#34;The Dramatic Instinct of Early Christianity,&#34; pp. 1-11.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Gold Medallion, Distinguished Service Awards, Birmingham-Southern College.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Governance of Public Higher Education in California</emph>. A Report prepared by the Academy for Educational Development, Inc., Oct. 8, 1968.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Harvard Library Bulletin</emph>. Vol, 3, # 3, Autumn 1949. &#34;The Future of Libraries in Academic Institutions,&#34; pp. 327-346.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Higher Education in a Changing World</emph>. &#34;Universities and World Affairs,&#34; pp. 69-79. (Addresses selected from the 1965 Conferences for the Visiting Fulbright-Hays Scholars in the United States).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Learning Today</emph>. &#34;Beyond Innovation, Forty Years of Teaching with Books&#34; by David J. Martz, Jr. (A New Look at Harvie Branscomb&#39;s <emph render="underline">Teaching with Books</emph>).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Library-College Journal</emph>. &#34;Curing the Campus Coronary,&#34; pp. 13-16.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">National Association of State Universities in the United States of America</emph>. &#34;A Two-Way Street Should Have Delivery at Both Ends,&#34; pp. 35-42.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Responsibility of Higher Education for Helping to Develop International Understanding</emph>. &#34;Introductory Statement,&#34; pp. 3-4. (A Series of Papers Presented at the Annual Meeting of the American Council on Education, Oct. 6, 1955).</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>&#34;Spiritual Values in Higher Education.&#34; An address delivered before the 51st Annual Meeting of the Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, Memphis, Tennessee, Dec. 13, 1946.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">The State of the University</emph>. A Report from the Chancellor to Alumni and Friends of Vanderbilt University, Sept. 1, 1947.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">UNESCO in a Decisive Decade</emph>. &#34;UNESCO and Education,&#34; pp. 4-9.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">Vanderbilt University - &#39;The Commodore&#39;s Best Investment</emph><emph render="super">1</emph>.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>SUPPLEMENT</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">CORRESPONDENCE</emph>: (Box 6, Folder 47)</unittitle>
</did>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1945</unitdate>
<unittitle>Aug. 27 to Dr. H. M. Lydenberg.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1947</unitdate>
<unittitle>Apr. 15 to Harold S. Vanderbilt.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>

<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1950</unitdate>
<unittitle>May 26 to Harold S. Vanderbilt.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1959</unitdate>
<unittitle>June 11 to Helen Ann Stavely; Oct. 21 to Winifred R. Long.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1962</unitdate>
<unittitle>Mar. 22 to Col. G. M. Dorland.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1963</unitdate>
<unittitle>Feb. 19 to Robert N. Buchanan, Jr.; Apr. 29 to Harold S. Vanderbilt Nov. 27 to Devereux Lake.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1964</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 2 to Mrs. Neil Cargil; Mar. 18 to Harold S. Vanderbilt; May 16 to Dr. Franz von Hildebrand; Dec. 26 to The Honorable J. L. Huang.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1965</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 7, June 3, June 11 to Harold S. Vanderbilt; Aug. 3 to Vice-President Hubert Humphrey; Aug. 6 to Richard A. Humphrey; Oct. 13 to Betty Hamilton (Mrs. John Andrew).</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1966</unitdate>
<unittitle>July 5 to Dr. Alberto Gianza Paz; July 6 to William J. Gill; July 9 to Eugene R. Black; July 26 to Dr. Ricardo Dstiaz Hochleitner; Nov. 16 to John J. Hertz; Dec. 14 to Harold [S. Vanderbilt].</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 5 to Dean John Harvey; May 5 to Mrs. Harold Huggins; May 25 to Frank Godchaux, III; Sept. 15 to John S. and R. D. Herbert, Jr.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 8 to Rob Roy [Purdy].</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1969</unitdate>
<unittitle>June 25 to Vanderbilt Board of Trust.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1970</unitdate>
<unittitle>Nov. 23 to Winfield Dunn.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1971</unitdate>
<unittitle>June 10 to Chancellor Alexander Heard; Aug. 3 to Sam Fleming.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1972</unitdate>
<unittitle>Mar. 24 to Jack; Nov. 13 to the Hon. John Eric Jonsson.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1973</unitdate>
<unittitle>Jan. 4 to The Hon. John Eric Jonsson; May 7 to Dr. Rufus Harris.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1974</unitdate>
<unittitle>July 9 to Dr. R. Gordon Hoxie; Oct. 3 to Herbert C. Stockham.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>1982</unitdate>
<unittitle>Aug. 2 to Ray Carlson.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
<c03 level="subseries">
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">47</container>
<unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
<unittitle>To the Reverend Minor E. Powers; to Mrs. Harold S. Vanderbilt.</unittitle>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="underline">INCOMING CORRESPONDENCE</emph>: (Box 6, Folder 48)</unittitle>
</did>
<index>
<indexentry>
<persname>Bess, Fred H.,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 29, 1981.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Betancur-Mejia, Gabriel,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 18, 1963.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Blum, Jeffery W.,</persname>
<ref>(1); (1980).</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Buchanan, Robert N., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 4, 1963.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Buek, Charles W.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 26, 1979 (to Alexander Heard).</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Califano, Joseph A., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 1, 1966.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Cater, Douglass,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 2, 1966.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Chandler, Robert K.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 26, 1962.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Cleveland, Harlan,</persname>
<ref>(2); Apr. 8, 1964, July 26, 1965.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Coniglio, John,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 21, 1979.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Cookey, S. J.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 6, 1965.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Dorland, G. M.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 12, 1962.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Ellington, Buford,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 13, 1967.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Elliott, Don R.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 17, 1957.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Forstman, Jack,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 29, 1980.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Garner, Robert L.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Jan. 18, 1968, Dec. 10, 1969.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Georgescu-Roegen, Nicholas,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 26, 1967.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Gill, William J.,</persname>
<ref>(2); June 22, July 12, 1966.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Halsema, James J.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 29, 1964.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hamilton, Betty,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 12, 1965.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Harrar, J. G.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 19, 1969.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Harris, Robert J.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 23, 1966.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Harris, Rufus C.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 6, 1973.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Harrison, Tinsley R.,</persname>
<ref>(5); Sept. 9, 1968, Jan. 22, Nov. 19, Dec. 3, Dec. 19, 1973.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Harwell, R. W.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Mar. 1, 1968.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Haury, Karl E.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 20, 1968.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hays, Bill,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 28, 1973.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Heard, Alexander,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 5, 1967 (memo to Professor Eugene Klatte).</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Heard, Alexander,</persname>
<ref>(1); Aug. 31, 1981.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Heard, Jean,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 9, 1977.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hertz, John J.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 25, 1966.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hildebrand, Franz v.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 3, 1964.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hill, S. Richardson, Jr., M.D.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 13, 1973.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hogarth, Charles P.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 17, 1972.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hope, Guy,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 28, 1966.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hornig, Donald F.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 29, 1965.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Horrocks, Norman,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 1, 1970.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Houston, Frank K.,</persname>
<ref>(5); Jan. 12, Jan. 30, Mar. 30, July 13, Sept. 9, 1970.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Howard, William F.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 11, 1973.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Hoxie, R. Gordon,</persname>
<ref>(6); Feb. 28, Apr. 30, Nov. 13, 1970, Aug. 4, 1972, June 15, July 6, 1973.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Huang, J. L.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 11, 1974.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Huggins, Juanita R. (Mrs. Howard),</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 27, 1967.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Humphrey, Hubert H.,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 28, 1965.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Humphrey, Richard A.,</persname>
<ref>(2); July 23, July 26, 1965.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Jacobson, Timothy,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 31, 1978.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Kite, Liz and Adkisson, Bill,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 21, 1974 (memo).</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Lan, Lun Thuy,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 18, 1961.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Ligon, Wister H.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 12, 1962.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Long, Winifred R.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 7, 1959.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>McCurdy, Charles P., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 20, 1959.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Mubyarto,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 19, 1961.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Nelson, J. Robert,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 21, 1959.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Ochsner, Alton,</persname>
<ref>(1); (1967).</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Parr, Grant,</persname>
<ref>(1); Dec. 7, 1950.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Powers, Minor E.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Dec. 22, 1961, Feb. 7, 1962.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Samuels, Essie,</persname>
<ref>(2); Dec. 7, 1973.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Stahlman, James G.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 6, 1966.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Stahlman, Mildred,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 25, 1973.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Stevenson, Alec B.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Oct. 20, 1961.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Swint, Henry Lee,</persname>
<ref>(4); June 1, 1970, Jan. 12, Oct. 19, 1972, May 21, 1976.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>TeSelle, Sallie M.,</persname>
<ref>(1); June 1, 1976.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Vanderbilt, Gertrude,</persname>
<ref>(2); Nov. 10, Nov. 16, 1970.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Vanderbilt, Harold S.,</persname>
<ref>(15); Mar. 25, July 13, 1964, Feb. 15, Mar. 5, Aug. 6, Nov. 15, 1965, July 7, Dec. 20, 1966, Apr. 24, Nov. 16, Nov. 20, Dec. 11, 1967, May 21, July 8, 1968, Feb. 9, 1970.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Vanderbilt, William H.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 2, 1970.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Vaughn, W. S.,</persname>
<ref>(2); Aug. 6, Aug. 12, 1970.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Wade, John W.</persname>
<ref>(1); May 4, 1955.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Wallace, Louis D.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 14, 1962.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Warren, A. Sam,</persname>
<ref>(1); Apr. 18, 1972 (to Vanderbilt <emph render="underline">Alumnus</emph>).</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Weinreb, Joseph, M.D.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Sept. 15, 1948.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>West, Elmer S.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 26, 1971.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Windham, A. B., Jr.,</persname>
<ref>(1); Feb. 12, 1962.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Youmans, John B.,</persname>
<ref>(1); May 15, 1950.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Young, Bert E.,</persname>
<ref>(1); July 26, 1946 (to Robert Lester).</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Unidentified (Herman),</persname>
<ref>(1); Nov. 7, 1978.</ref>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
<persname>Speeches, papers, reports, programs, minutes of meetings, and newspaper clippings (Miscellaneous): (Box 6, Folder 49 and Box 7, Folder 50).</persname>
</indexentry>
</index>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
