<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US"></eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Hawkins, Robert Martyr Papers</titleproper>
        <titleproper>Finding Aid for the Robert Martyr Hawkins Papers</titleproper>
        <author></author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2013</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>419 21st Avenue South</addressline>
          <addressline>Nashville, TN 37203-2427</addressline>
          <addressline>specialcollections@vanderbilt.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL:
            <extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.vanderbilt.edu/speccol/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.library.vanderbilt.edu/speccol/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Robert Martyr Hawkins Papers</unittitle>
      <unitid>MSS.0199</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.36 linear_feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate>multiple</unitdate>
    </did>
    <dsc type="othertype">
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <unittitle>Correspondence, outgoing</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>October 24, 1931. Outgoing correspondence of 1 letter, a typescript carbon copy.</p>
            <p>Correspondence, incoming. Incoming correspondence of 4 letters, alphabetically arranged. Letters are typescript. 1 letter is incomplete, 1 is without surname.</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <unittitle>Sermons</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>Include approximately 350 sermons, mostly holograph. 329 have titles, alphabetically arranged. 5 are without titles, and are arranged at the end of the sermons, alone with commencement, baccalaureate, and fragmentary sermons.</p>
            <p>Abel, Acceptable Unto God; Abundant Pardon; The Account of Our Stewardship; All In Love; The All Surpassing Claims of Christ; All Things New; The Alleviation of the Ills of Life; Arise, Shine, For Thy Light Is Come; Asking In His Name; Aspects of
              the Christian Life; Blessed Are the Poor In Spirit, For Theirs Is the Kingdom of Heaven; The Blessed Separateness of God's People; The Blessing of Abraham; The Blood of the Covemant; The Broad and Narrow Ways; The Bruised Reed and the Smoking Flax;
              Building a Life; Caiaphas, High Priest That Year; Can We Be Christians?; Careful Living; The Changeless Word In the Changing World; The Children of God; Choose Life and Live; Christ in the Home; Christ The Bread of Life For Our Hungry Souls; Christ
              Our Peace; Christ The Perfect Sacrifice; Christian Development; Christian Giving; Christian Optimism; The Christian Religion Essentially Missionary; Christian Stewardship; The Christlike Mind; Christ's Kingdom Not of This World; Christ Is Mediation;
              Christ's Sufferings Reasonable; The Church and the Laboring Man; Come, Learn, Rest; Come Unto Me and Rest; Complete in Christ; The Consciousness of God's Watchfulness Ennobles Life; Consider Jesus Christ; Contrast Between Yielding to Temptation and
              Enduring Temptation; A Contrast Picture of God; The Cost of Discip;eship; The Crown Laid Up; A Cup of Cold Water or, Principles of Christian Service; The Cure of A Deaf and Dumb Man; Dedication; The Deeper Meaning of Life; Deliver Us From the Evil
              One; The Despoiling of Death; The Destiny of Humanity Achieved Thru Faith in Christ; The Destiny of Man in the Light of the Love of God and Human Faith; The Disadvantages and Possibilities of Youth; The Doom of Esau; The Duty of Man; Earth Fades But
              God Abides; Enoch, The Superlative of Humanity; Eve, The Mother of Human Mischief; The Expansiveness of God's Purposes; Experience the Basis of Testimony; The Faith and Failings of Abraham; The Faith Righteousness of Abraham; The Fatherhood of God;
              Festus, A Good Govenor; Filial Imitation of God; The Final Judgement; The Final Verdict; Fishers of Men; The Flesh Driven Out By The Spirit; Follow Me; The Foolishness of God; Forgive Us Our Debts As We Forgive Our Debtors; Forgiveness, The Divine
              Fallacy; Friendship With Jesus; The Gift of A Son; Give Us This Day Our Daily Bread; The Glorified Life and Death; The Glory of the Ministry; Go Where He Sends; God Appointed Us To Salvation; God Bless America; God Desires Goodness; God Our Applicted
              Savior; God Our Father; God Our Shield and Reward; God's . Double Dwelling Place; God's Eternal Plan For the World; God's Farreaching Train; God's Fellow Laborers; God's Love For The World; God's Mehtod of Dealing With Sin; God's Unnatural Chrildren;
              God's Witness To His Son; The Golden Rule, Its Restraint, Its Inspiration; Grace and Truth in Jesus; The Grace and Truth of The Gospel; The Great Commission; The Greatness of John the Baptist; The Guiding Word; The Harvest of Life Or Death; Have
              Faith in God; He Saved Others; Healed By His Stripes; Hearing and Doing; Heavenly Citizenship; Help Thou Mine Unbelief; Herod the Great; The Hidden Kingdom; His Life, Our Light; His Yoke, His Lesson, His Rest; Holy Resolution; The Homiletic
              Commentary; Human Ingratitude for Divine Mercies; Human Sin, the Barrier Between Man and God; I Commend You To God And His Word; I Love The Lord; The Illumined Life; The Importance of Repentance; The Impossible Task of Faith; "In the Fullness of His
              Stature"; Issac, The Average Man; Issaci The Incarnation of Ordinary Virtures; Jacob, God's Making of a Prince; Jesus The Assurance of Our Unrealized Ideals; Jesus The Comforter; Joseph, Great Through Adversity; Joshua's Three Paths; Joy In Trials;</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">2</container>
          <unittitle>The Joy of Easter</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>The Joy Set Before Us; The Judgement Seat of Pilate; Justification By Faith; Justification of Evil; Keeping Up With the Times; The Keys of the Kingdom; The King and the Far Country; Knowing And Doing: The Knowledge of Christ; Lead Us Not Into
              Temptation; Learn To Do Well or The Education of the . Soul; Led In Triumph In Christ; A Leper Cleansed; Leprosy and Sin; Lessons From Adam; The Lessons of the Storms; Life As A Race; A Life of Love; A Little Child Shall Lead Them; Eo, I Am With You
              Always, Even Unto The End of the World; The Longest Word in the Bible Eternity; Lord, I Believe, Help Thou Mine Unbelief; The Lord Our Portion in Life and In Death; The Lord's Prayer Incidental Aspects; The Lord's Prayer, Its Teaching Concerning God
              and Life; The Lord's Remembrances; The Lord's Sermon; Losing Doubt Thru Service; The Man of Sorrows; Man Shall Not Live By Bread Alone; Mary Magdalene, A Lesson for Easter Night; Mary, The Mother of Jesus; The Meaning of Discipleship; The Meaning of
              Easter; The Meaning of the Resurrection; Melchizedek, Priest of Eternity; The Message of the Incarnation; The Ninistering Master; Missionary prayer; Moses' Wise Choice; My Church; The Name of Jesus; The Nature of Prayer; The Necesity of Watchfulness;
              The Need of Normal Christian Lives - or John the Baptist and Jesus; The New Birth; Noah, A Type of A Man's Relation To God and His Fellowmen; Not Ashamed of the Gospel; Not To Destroy, But to Fulfil; Not Your Own; An 0. T. Lesson on Prayer; The
              Observance of the Lord's Day; Of This World, Or Not?; Only As Little Children; Opportunities and Hindrances As Seen in Paul's Ephesian Ministry; Opportunity and Responsibility; Our Bold Approach; Our Faith in the Reality and the Rewards of God; ' Our
              Heavenly Father; Our Life Work, God's Glory; Our Manifestation With Christ, Our Life; Our Peace in Him; Outlines And Briefs (outlines of several sermons); Overcoming the World Thur Faith; The Pastor's Helpers; Paul's Sermon To Felix; Perfect In The
              Way; The Perfection of God; Peter's Denial and Repentance; The Place of the Church of Christ; The Poor Man's Market; Practical Christianity; Prayer of Our Lord Supposedly on the Return of the Seventy; The Preeminence of Christ in the Christian Life;
              Prepare Ye The Way of The Lord; A Psalm of Deliverance; Revekah; Redeeming the Time; Redigging the Wells of Life; Remarks On the General Rules; The Revelation of the Unknown God; The Reward of Faithful Service; The Rich Young Ruler of Christ' Lesson
              on Giving; The Rich Young Ruler or Life's Supreme Question; The Riches of the Reproach of Christ; The Salt of the Earth; The Light of the World; Salvation; The Satisfaction of the Longing of the Human Soul; The Secret of Moses' Endurance; The Secret
              of a Truly Great Life, John The Baptist; Seeking First the Kingdom; Simon, The Cross Bearer of Our Lord; Sin; The Sin Bearing Lamb of God; Sin Due to a Lack of the Knowledge of Lod; Sincere Worship and Holy Living; The Six-Winged Seraphs; The Social
              Message and Mission of Xy; The Spirit of Conviction; The Spiritual Life; Spiritual Power For Witnessing; Spiritual Profit and Loss; Spiritual Vision; The Stewardship of God's Blessing; Stories of the Atonement; The Story of Cain; The Struggle And
              Triumph of God's Purpose; Studies in Mark (# 1-5, 7-28, 30-35, 37-41, 43-52,); Sufficiency of the Strength in Christ; The Sure Richness of Our Calling; The Surrendered Life; Testing Our Lives; Things Old and New; The Three Elements of Human Life; Thy
              Will Be Done; The Transfiguration; The Transfiguration of War; Tried Temple Pillars; The Triumph of Patient Obedience; The Triumphal Entry; The True Missionary Motive; The Two Aspects of The Christian Life Represented by Martha and Mary; The Two
              Baptisms; The Unity of God an Incontestable Claim Upon the Full Allegiance of Every Man; The Urgent Invitation; The Visit of the Magi; Visiting the Afflicted; Waiting on the Lord; The Way, The Truth, The Life; The Ways of God; "What Christ Is To Us";
              What Does It Mean To Be Saved?; What is Sin? What Must I Do To Be Saved?; What The Law Could Not Do; What Think Ye of The Christ?; When Shall We Live?; Who Is On The Lord's Side; Who Needs A Physician?; The Way of Salvation; Willing Workers; Wiser
              Than Soloman; Witnesses of the Resurrection; The Wonder of Unbelief; The Wonders of the Christian Life; The World's Only Salvation; Worshipping the Lord; Ye Will Not Come Unto Me.</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">3</container>
          <unittitle>Manuscripts</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>Typescript and holograph. 4 manuscripts alphabetically arranged by title. First draft Pauline data; Jesus and Isaiah; the recovery of the historical Paul; the rise of the Old Testament.</p>
            <p>Papers.Gonsist of 7 typescript and carbon copies. Arranged alphabetically by title. Charles Kingsley, A Minister of Christ; The First Book of Samuel; The Psychology of Grace and Inspiration; The Rejection of Israel; A Summary of the Prohibition
              Question; Thomas Carlyle; To Kat'erne.</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">4</container>
          <unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>Approximately 200 loose pages, filled with magazine and newspaper clippings.</p>
            <p>Published articles. Consist of 3, alphabetically arranged by title. The Galatian Gospel of Mark; Romans; A Reinterpretation. Book Reviews. 4 typescript, carbon copies. Alphabetically arranged by title. How Came The Bible by E. J. Goodspeed; The
              Gospel According to Gamaliel by G. Heard; The New Testament by F. A. Spencer; Why I Prefer The American Revised Version of the Bible.</p>
            <p>Essay. Holograph, 4 pages, Titled Life In Britain. Prayer. An Easter Prayer.</p>
            <p>Class notes. Holograph notes while a student at Edinburgh University.</p>
            <p>Certificates and Diploma. Certificates of Elder and Deacon in the Methodist Episcopal Church South. Also included are a local preachers license and a Diploma from Edinburgh University.</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">5</container>
          <unittitle>Lecture and research notes</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>Consist of approximately 800 pages of lectures, lecture notes, and research notes, much of which pertain to courses taught by</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">6</container>
          <unittitle>Hawkins while at Vanderbilt</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>Material is typescript and holograph. Research notes follow lecture notes, fragmentary material is found last.</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">7</container>
          <unittitle>New Testament Studies</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>Material includes holograph and typescript notes and essays on Paul, Mark, and Jesus. There is an untitled typescript paper, 6 chapters in length on Paul. Material also includes the text of the Pauline letters. The studies in Mark consist of 5,
              and numerous lectures on the gospel of Mark which were given in the rural church school of Vanderbilt University in 1928, 1935, 1936. The studies about Jesus consist of 5 typescript, carbon sections of 3 pages each.</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">7</container>
          <unittitle>Sunday School materials</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>Include expository notes, explanations and outlines for the uniform lessons. Subject matter consists of miscellaneous studies in both Old and New Testaments. Material is mostly typescript and carbon copies.</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">7</container>
          <unittitle>Works by others</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>Include reader's reports on 2 of Hawkin's works, The Recovery of the Historical Paul, and The Rise of the Old Testament. Also included is a paper written by Dechard Henry Turner, Jr., for New Testament seminar, titled
              <emph render="underline">The</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Correlation</emph>
              <emph render="underline">of</emph>
              <emph render="underline">the</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Key</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Scriptural</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Reference</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Used</emph>
              <emph render="underline">by</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Contemporary</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Scholarship</emph>
              <emph render="underline">In</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Its</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Reconstruction</emph>
              <emph render="underline">of</emph>
              <emph render="underline">the</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Pauline</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Gospel</emph>
              <emph render="underline">With</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Our</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Categories</emph>
              <emph render="underline">of</emph>
              <emph render="underline">"Spurious"</emph>
              <emph render="underline">and</emph>
              <emph render="underline">"Genuine"</emph>
              <emph render="underline">Materials</emph>, and a final examination paper by J. E. Sellers, dated March 25, 1955. Material is mostly typescript, some carbon copies.</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">8</container>
          <unittitle>Offprints and reprints</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>Include 1 offprint, 2 reprints, and 1 preprint. Arranged alphabetically by title. Some are autographed by the author. Divine Kingship in the Ancient Near East; A review article, by Theodore H. Gaster; How Well Did the Synoptic Evangelists Know the
              Synagogue?, by Sylvan D. Schwartzman; In History or Beyond History, by C. C. McCown; Thirty Years of New Testament Study, by C. H. Dodd.</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <container type="box">8</container>
          <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>Includes the annual reports if the Southwest Missouri Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church, 1910 - 1918; Several church programs; a typescript carbon copy of a plan to establish a memorial collection in the JUL in honor of the parents of
              Robert Martyr Hawkins; a transcript from the records of the Vanderbilt School of Religion of the credits of R. M. Hawkins 1907 - 1910; Cash account kept on Hawkins while in Edinburgh; syllabus for courses for the School of Missions; course evaluation
              written by students of Hawkins; magazine clippings; publishers' announcement.
            </p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
