<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
<eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
<eadid countrycode="US"></eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper type="filing">Hill, John McMurry Papers</titleproper>
<titleproper>Finding Aid for the The John M. Hill Collection</titleproper>
<author>Gerald K. Wade</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher>Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books</publisher>
<p><date>Undated</date></p>
<address>
<addressline>419 21st Avenue South</addressline>
<addressline>Nashville, TN 37203-2427</addressline>
<addressline>specialcollections@vanderbilt.edu</addressline>
<addressline>URL:
<extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.vanderbilt.edu/speccol/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.library.vanderbilt.edu/speccol/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
</address>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<langmaterial>
<language langcode="eng">English</language>
</langmaterial>
<repository>
<corpname>Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books</corpname>
</repository>
<unittitle>The John M. Hill Collection</unittitle>
<unitid>MSS.0209</unitid>
<physdesc altrender="whole">
<extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.55 Linear Feet</extent>
</physdesc>
<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
</did>
<bioghist>
<head>A Brief Evaluation</head>
<p>The list of materials left JUL by John M. Hill is carefully made, with helpful cross references. It is apparent that the unique value of the Collection lies in its inclusion of many titles of the 16th and 17th centuries. A large number of the volumes are entirely unavailable for purchase today; during the past two decades and more university libraries in the United States have taken about all of the earlier Spanish books that could be found, as book dealers&#39; catalogues show.</p>
<p>Professor Walter Poesse of Indiana University, formerly Professor Hill&#39;s student and then his colleague, reported for a faculty committee after Professor Hill&#39;s death that the latter&#39;s interests were largely in lexicography and the drama of the 16th and 17th centuries. The list of the Hill books in the JUL Collection bears this out. For example, there are no less than six editions of the Spanish Academy Dictionary, beginning with the first edition in six volumes of 1726-39. Specialized studies of the Spanish language are numerous: representative volumes are the Academy Grammar of 1917, the <emph render="underline">Plan General</emph> of 1914 for an historical dictionary (a plan never carried out), the Aguado <emph render="underline">Glosario sobre Juan Ruiz</emph>, Aicardo&#39;s 1906 list of words left out of the Academy dictionary, Alba&#39;s <emph render="underline">Suplemento de todos los Diccionarios</emph> (1918), the rare Aldrete <emph render="underline">Del origen</emph> ... <emph render="underline">de la lengua catellana</emph> (1674), Alemany&#39;s <emph render="underline">Vocabulario de G&#972;ngora</emph>. There are also the eight-volume <emph render="underline">Anejos de la Revista de Filolog&#237;a espa&#241;ola</emph> on aspects of the language and literature, many <emph render="underline">Cancioneros</emph> (ancient ballad collections), Baist&#39;s <emph render="underline">Die spanische Sprache</emph> Bello&#39;s famous grammar. Numerous studies of diclects appear: Garrote&#39;s <emph render="underline">Dialecto vulgar leon&#233;s</emph>. Bayo&#39;s <emph render="underline">Vocabulario criollo-espa&#241;ol sudamericano</emph>, Besses&#39; <emph render="underline">Diccionario de argot espa&#241;ol</emph>. Ancient dictionaries are representedt: Las Casas&#39; 1570 <emph render="underline">Vocabulario de las dos lenguas toscana y castellana</emph>, Covarrubias&#39; 1611 <emph render="underline">Tesoro</emph> and Its 1674 reprint with additions, Minsheu&#39;s <emph render="underline">Dictionarie in Spanish and English</emph> (London, 1599), Oudin&#39;s <emph render="underline">Tesoro de las dos lenguas espa&#241;ola y francesa</emph> of 1675, Stevens&#39; <emph render="underline">New Spanish and English Dictionary</emph> of 1707.</p>
<p>A selection of the most valuable volumes would include the above of the 16th and 17th centuries and also the 1628 edition of Rengifo&#39;s <emph render="underline">Arte po&#233;tica espa&#241;ola</emph>, the 1624 edition of Barthius&#39; <emph render="underline">Pornoboscodidascalus Latinus</emph>, Mexia&#39;s Silva de varia lecci&#243;n of 1662 and hie <emph render="underline">Treaaurie of Ancient and Moderne Times</emph> (London, 1613). The famous satirist Quevedo is represented by a 1650 edition of his <emph render="underline">Parnaso espa&#241;ol</emph>, a 1670 edition of <emph render="underline">Las tres musas</emph>, a 1686 French edition of <emph render="underline">Les visions</emph>, a 1642 printing of his <emph render="underline">Advertencias</emph>. Other volumes of the 16th and 17th centuries might be mentioned. Especially noteworthy is Lebrija&#39;a Latin dictionary of 1585, as also the 1604 edition of Alem&#225;n&#39;s <emph render="underline">Guzm&#225;n de Alforache</emph> and Diocsorides&#39;1695 book on medicine; there is also a 1638 edition of Gonz&#225;lez D&#225;vila&#39;s <emph render="underline">Historia del Rel Don Henrique el Tercero</emph>.</p>
<p>Professor Hill&#39;s interest in the older drama is well represented by the <emph render="underline">Teatro antiguo espa&#241;ol</emph> (Madrid, 1916-35), by Garc&#237;a de la Huerta&#39;s saventeen-voulme <emph render="underline">Theatro espa&#241;ol</emph> of 1785-86 with plays by many authors, by several other works on the theater by Spanish and foreign scholars: Bonilla&#39;s <emph render="underline">Los bacantes</emph>, Lord Holland&#39;s now rare works on Lope de Vega, Restori&#39;s studies in Italy of the 17th-century <emph render="underline">comedia</emph> of Spain&#39;s Golden Age. There are several histories, collections and anthologies by the older dramatists. There are twenty <emph render="underline">comedias sueltas</emph> (single editions) of several dramatists. Lope de Vega has thirty-nine entries in the Hill list; Calder&#243;n, Tirso, Moreto and others have almost as many.</p>
<p>The breadth of Professor Hill&#39;s interest beyond lexicography and the ancient drama is indicated by his acquisition of twelve volumes of <emph render="underline">Incunables Po&#233;ticos Castallanos</emph> and the many Spanish classics in them, by fourteen editions of the first picaresque novel, <emph render="underline">El Lazarillo de Tormes</emph>. by fifteen volumes of <emph render="underline">Libros de anta&#241;o</emph> (1872-1900). There are twelve entries in the Hill list of <emph render="underline">Proverbios</emph>, six volumes of <emph render="underline">Publicaciones de la Revista de Filolog&#237;a espa&#241;ola</emph> (1917-26), numerous works of famous Spanish scholars like Men&#233;ndez y Pelayo, Men&#233;ndez Pidal, Gallardo, Rodr&#237;guez Mar&#237;a, Cotarelo. There are French scholars like M&#233;rim&#233;e, Morel-Fatio, Foulch&#233;-Delbosc, German Hispaniste like von Schaok and Schaeffer, the renowned English soholar Fitzmaurice-Kelly, also George Borrow (<emph render="underline">The Bible in Spain</emph>) (three volumes, 1843) and Martin Hume the historian, Restori the Italian, mentioned above.</p>
<p>There are works on Spanish traditions and folklore, on customs and character. The list has travel books by Brunei and Madame d&#39;Aulnoy. The picaresque novel is represented by many titles, as are the <emph render="underline">Celestina</emph>. Cervantes (twenty-five entries), <emph render="underline">The Poem of the Cid</emph> (twelve entries). Collections are numerous, some of them extensive and now unobtainable in the marke: twenty-one volumes of the Bibliotheca Hisp&#225;nica, ten of the Bibliotheca Romanica, forty-three of the Cl&#225;sicos castellanos, twelve of Bonilla&#39;s Cl&#225;sicos de la Literatura espa&#241;ola, six of the Colecci&#243;n de Autores espa&#241;oles, thirty-two of the Colecci&#243;n de Escritores castellanos, eight of the Sociedad de Bibli&#243;filos madrile&#241;os, eleven of Op&#250;sculos literarios rar&#237;simos by Duque y Marqu&#233;s, 115 volumes of Hispanic Notes and Monographs.</p>
<p>To be found in the list is the valuable catalogue of the Boston Library of the Ticknor Collection. Among periodicals there are the three volumes of <emph render="underline">El averiguador</emph> of 1867-68 and the four volumes of <emph render="underline">El averigador univarsal</emph> of 1879-82. The number of pamphlets and offprints totals 1094. Various university publications on Hispanic matters are here, among them California&#39;s, Colorado&#39;s, Iowa&#39;s, Nebraska&#39;s, New Mexico&#39;s, Pennsylvania&#39;s and Texas&#39;s.</p>
<p>The above items represent only the most obviously outstanding parts of the valuable Hill Collection, surely one of the best in the United States. It would be an appreciated public service if the Collection compiled by the JUL staff could be published (possibly by the Vanderbilt University Press).</p>
</bioghist>

<scopecontent>
<head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<table frame="none">
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colnum="1" colname="1" align="left" colwidth="50pt"/>
<colspec colnum="2" colname="2" align="left" colwidth="100pt"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry colname="1">Sept. 3, 1887</entry>
<entry colname="2">Born in Dresden, Tennessee</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1908</entry>
<entry colname="2">Received A.B. degree, Vanderbilt University.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1910</entry>
<entry colname="2">Received A.B. degree, Vanderbilt University.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1912</entry>
<entry colname="2">Received PhD. in romance languages from the University of Wisconsin.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1914 - 1915</entry>
<entry colname="2">Spent at University of Madrid.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1915 - 1916</entry>
<entry colname="2">Spent at University of Paris.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1916</entry>
<entry colname="2">Returned to United States and assumed position of Associate Professor of romance languages at Indiana University.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1934</entry>
<entry colname="2">Appointed head of Department of Spanish at Indiana University.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1951</entry>
<entry colname="2">Resigned from headship.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1958</entry>
<entry colname="2">Retired from teaching as Professor Emeritus.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">Nov. 6, 1966</entry>
<entry colname="2">Died</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<note>
<p>Professor Hill was especially devoted to Hispanic literature of the 16th and 17th centuries, the drama in particular, and to Spanish lexicography.</p>
<p>Member: Modern Language Association; American Association of Teachers of Spanish and Portuguese; Modern Humanities Research Association; Phi Beta Kappa; Alpha Tau Omega; Hispanic Society of America.</p>
</note>
</scopecontent>
<scopecontent>
<head>Description of Series</head>
<table frame="none">
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colnum="1" colname="1" align="left" colwidth="50pt"/>
<colspec colnum="2" colname="2" align="left" colwidth="100pt"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1</entry>
<entry colname="2">Correspondence - Incoming. Incoming correspondence of 2 letters and 5 post cards, dating from 1916 to 1931. The correspondence is alphabetically arranged: Cabre, Ramon, Jan. 25, 1916; Faudo, Jose Manuel Lope, Aug., 1916; The Hispanic Society of America, Oct. 8, 1931; Sarpy, Melletta, Apr. 4, 1922; 2 illegible signatures, May 4, 1922, Apr. 8, 1929.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1</entry>
<entry colname="2">Memorial Resolution. There is a xeroxed copy of this resolution, marked &#8220;Fac. Counc. Doc. No. 13 1966-1967&#8221;, which was prepared by Theodore E. Dorf, Walter Poesse, Richard S. Sherman, and Merle E. Simmons.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1</entry>
<entry colname="2">Plays. There is a photoduplicated copy of <emph render="underline">El Cavallo Vos Han Muerto</emph>, comedia famosa de Lope De Vega Carpi&#243;, and a typescript carbon copy of <emph render="underline">Si El Caballo Vos Han Muerto</emph>, comedia famosa de Luis Velez De Guevara.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1</entry>
<entry colname="2">Research Notes. Approximately 150 pages of holographic notes in Spanish.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1</entry>
<entry colname="2">Notebook. A typescript list of books in the Spanish collection of John M. Hill, dated Oct. 1, 1958, is found in this notebook.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="1">1</entry>
<entry colname="2">Post Cards. Approximately 100 picture post cards of New York City, Washington, D.C., Versailles, Tangiers, Spain, and Portugal.</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</scopecontent>
</archdesc>
</ead>