<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
<eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
<eadid countrycode="US"></eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper type="filing">Sanborn, Herbert Charles Papers</titleproper>
<titleproper>Finding Aid for the Herbert Charles Sanborn Papers</titleproper>
<author></author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher>Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books</publisher>
<p><date>undated</date></p>
<address>
<addressline>419 21st Avenue South</addressline>
<addressline>Nashville, TN 37203-2427</addressline>
<addressline>specialcollections@vanderbilt.edu</addressline>
<addressline>URL:
<extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.vanderbilt.edu/speccol/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.library.vanderbilt.edu/speccol/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
</address>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<langmaterial>
<language langcode="eng">English</language>
</langmaterial>
<repository>
<corpname>Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books</corpname>
</repository>
<unittitle>Herbert Charles Sanborn Papers</unittitle>
<unitid>MSS.0382</unitid>
<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
<physdesc altrender="whole">
<extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15.54 linear feet</extent>
</physdesc>
<unitdate>undated</unitdate>
</did>
<dsc type="othertype">
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Correspondence</title> - <title render="underline">Outgoing</title></unittitle>
<unitdate>October 24, 1934 - January 27, 1966</unitdate>
</did>
<note>
<p>Outgoing correspondence of 129 letters. Chronologically arranged by days and months, letters are typescript, holograph, and carbon copies. Thirty-three undated letters found at end of outgoing correspondence.</p>
</note>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">1-17</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Correspondence</title> - <title render="underline">Incoming</title></unittitle>
</did>
<note>
<p>Incoming correspondence of 4,326 letters, 235 post cards, and 70 telegrams. Alphabetically arranged, letters are typescript, holograph, and carbon copies. There are several circular and mimeographed. Letters signed with initials only and with 1 name only are found at end. Illegible signatures found last.</p>
</note>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">17-19</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Research</title> <title render="underline">Notes</title></unittitle>
</did>
<note>
<p>Approximately 2000 pages of holograph and typescript notes on a variety of subjects, including philosophy, psychology, communism, internationalism, dashunds, and goats.</p>
</note>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">19</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Notebooks</title> <title render="underline">and</title> <title render="underline">Scrapbooks</title></unittitle>
</did>
<note>
<p>Material consists of 4 holograph and typescript notebooks, and 2 scrapbooks which belonged to Sanborn.</p>
</note>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">20-22</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Writings</title> <title render="underline">by</title> <title render="underline">Sanborn</title>
</unittitle>
</did>
<note>
<p>Writings by Sanborn. Material includes 101 published and unpublished works by Sanborn. There are essays, leaflets, reprints, articles, book reviews, rough drafts and manuscripts, alphabetically arranged by title.</p>
<p>Academic Libertinism; Aesthetics and Civilization; Aesthetics and Metaphysics; The American Way; Are There Any Individuals?; The Assassination of the Republic; An Attempt to Develop A Phylogenetic Habit; Attempts to Develop a Phylogenetic Habit; The Basis of Consolidation; The Biology of the Race Problem; A Review; Communisn and the Metro-Plan; Communism and the Problem of Academic Freedom; Communism, Internationalism and Freedom; A Critical Review of Publications in "The Politician" and "American Opinion"; "The Curse of The Foundations"; Dachshund Notes; The Dachshund or Teckel;</p>
<p>Dachshunds; Dachshunds at Albany; The Danger from Rabies; Vaccination; Davenport&#8217;. Contribution to the Use of Graphical Methods in Logic; De Mortuis nil nisi bonus; Democracy, Science, and Philosophy; The Democratic Control of Education; Desegregation and Ethics; Dingler&#8217;s Last Discovery; Dingler&#8217;s Methodical Philosophy; The Dogma of Non-Transference; The Doom and Nemesis of Our Internationalism; Down-East Spirituals and Others by George Pullen Jackson, reviewed by Sanborn; Dr. Sanborn&#8217;s Platform; Education that Universalizes; Essays on Faith and Morals, Pgrgmatism, Radical Empiricism and A Pluralistic Universe, 3 reviews by Sanborn; The Ethics of Hugo Dingier; An Examination of William Stern&#8217;s Philosophy; Fichte&#8217;s Clssed Commercial State; The Fouteenth Amendment; Freedom Forgotten and Remembered by Helmut Kuhn, reviewed by Sanborn; The Function of Clothing and of Bodily Adornment; The Function of language Study in Liberal Education; The Function of Philosophy in Liberal Education; German Philosophy and Politics by John Dewey, reviewed by Sanborn; The Great Conspiracy to Destroy the United States; Die Grundlagen einer experimentelle Bildungspsychologie by Werner Straub, reviewed by Sanborn; The Hidden Hand; Horace Williams Gadfly of Chapel Hill by Robert Watson, reviewed by Sanborn; Hugo Dingier - What is Conventialism?; The Inheritance of Song In Birds; The International Conspiracy; Internationalism and Zionism; Internationalism - By Way of U.S. Aid to Education; Is the Reaction of the South Emotional?; Dant&#8217;s Contributions to Science; Lines for a "Dying Republic"; Man and His Works by Edward Lee Thron-Dike, reviewed by Sanborn; The Meaning fo Internationalism; The Meaning of Philosophy of the Southern Association for Philosophy and Psychology; The Meeting Point of Philosophy and Psychology; Methodology and Aesthetics; Methodology and the Monkey States; Methodology and the Problem of Language; Methodology and The Problem of Musical Expression; Methodology and the Problem of the Southern Society for Philosophy and Psychology; The Monkey States; Music; A New Dachshund Star; Observations of Apparently Unlearned Behavior; On War by Karl Von Clausewitz, reviewed by Sanborn; La Philosophical Tranactions 1773; Philosophia Perennis Edited by Fritz-Joachim Von Rintelen, reviewed by Sanborn; La Philosophie de l&#8217;art Classique by Draguicha Lapcevic, Reviewed by Sanborn; Philosophies and Psychologies; The Philosophy of G.E. Moore; The Philosophy of Wilhelm Wundt; Post Election Relections; The Principles of Power by Giuglielmo Ferrere, Reviewed by Sanborn; The Problem of Language; The Problem of Psychic Reality; Problems of Constitutionality; Psychology and Epistemology; Rabies by Leslie T. Webster, Reviewed by Sanborn; The Rabies Menace; The Rabies Racket; Religion, Psychology And Philosophy; A Review of Aristotelian Aesthetics; Review of "Rabies"; Selected Paintings by Rembrandt, Reviewed by Sanborn; A Side-Light On The Katharsis; The Spirit of Martin Luther; The Spirit of Tragic Drama; Sunma Jus, Sumna Injuria; Teckel Note. Tendencies in American Dachshund Breeding; Thucydides On History As Philosophy; Tragedy as a Work of Art; What the United Nations Really Is; Which War are we At or About to be At?; 6 untitled writings.</p>
</note>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">22-24</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Business</title> <title render="underline">Papers</title></unittitle>
</did>
<note>
<p>Approximately 1,000 items, including bank statements, bank deposit tickets, bills and receipts, income tax papers, royalty statements, stock certificates and automobile insurance papers, chronologically arranged by year, from 1908-1963.</p>
</note>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">24</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Newspaper</title> <title render="underline">and</title> <title render="underline">Magazine</title> <title render="underline">Clippings</title> <title render="underline">of</title> <title render="underline">Articles</title> <title render="underline">by</title> <title render="underline">Sanborn</title>. Material includes approximately 50 clippings, dealing with a variety of subjects, from fluoridation to dachshunds to politics.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">25</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Newspaper</title> <title render="underline">and</title> <title render="underline">Magazine</title> <title render="underline">Clippings</title> <title render="underline">About</title> <title render="underline">Sanborn</title>. Material consists of approximately 25 clippings about Herbert Charles Sanborn.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">25</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Reprints</title> <title render="underline">and</title> <title render="underline">Offprints</title>. Thirty-four, alphabetically arranged by title: A Call to Action In American Education; Can Roman Catholics Be Loyal to Both America and the Vatican? Carlos Everett Conant; Change In Size Of The After-Image Induced In Total Darkness; Creative Thought In Artists; The Designation Of Combination Tones; The Emergence of Racial Genetics; Ends Versus Goals in Foreign-Language Study; Eurhythmic; Functional Logic; If the U.S. Be cones 51% Catholic!; Man the Measure; Migratory Behavior In Song Sparrows; Morea and the Moon; Nesting Success During Three Seasons In A Song Sparrow Population; A Note on Symbolic Inversion; Proceedings. of the Forty- Third Annual Meeting Of The Southern Society For Philosophy and Psychology; Proceedings of The Forty-Fifth Annual Meeting Of The Southern Society For Philosophy And Psychology; Proceedings of the Forty-Sixth Annual Meeting Of The Southern Society For Philosophy and Psychology; The Psychological Laboratory of The University of Texas; The Psychology of Music; Racial Attitudes Among White And Negro Children In A Deep-South Standard Metropolitan Area; The Racial History Of Scandinavia; Relations Between The Sexes In Song Sparrows; Remarks About The Phenomenological Program; The Role Of Graphical Methods In The History Of Logic; The Social Aspects Of Population Dynamics; Society, Ideas and Cultural Achievement; Some Refeections on Freedom; The Study Of Wild Animals Under Controlled Conditions; The Theodosian Code and Novels and the Sirmondian Constitutions; The Theory Of Territorialism And Its Development; Who Is To Dear Primary Responsibility For The Psychological Disorders?; Yogurt.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">25-26</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Writings</title> <title render="underline">by</title> <title render="underline">Others</title>. Material consists of 44 works by others, including poems, essays, and research paper. Alphabetically arranged by title, writings are typescript, holograph, and carbon copies. Acetonemia, A Vitamin Deficiency; Aesthetics And The Biology Of The Fleeting Moment; The Atlantic City Dog how; Aus dem Amerikanischen Buchereiwesen; Ballade en toc a la Lune attique; The Bankrupt; Berkeleyan Aspects of Wordsworth&#8217;s Thought; Bishop Oxnam Flunks His Test; Prepared "Proof" of Anti-Communism not Convincing; The Breathless Void; Carolina-Virginia Dog Show Circuit April 14-27, 1942; Contr Dingier Pro Dingier; Educational Freedom - Or - Educational Control?; General Terms In Geography; The Goats in Russia; Harry Truman&#8217;s President&#8217;s Commission On Higher Education - 1947; Hermitage; How To Philosophize; Introduction To The Study Of The Electrophysiology Of The African Negre 1st die Entwicklung der Lebewesen eine Idee Oder eine Tatsache?; Long Live The Irish; The Man In The Gap; May Jones Take the Air; The Mortain Counterattack; My Day; Nationalism nd World Citizenship, Striking A Sane Balance; The Nervous Man; One fundamental; The Philosopher&#8217;s Scales; A Plea For Psychologists&#8217; Interest In Psychical Research; Plowman&#8217;s Folly Refuter The Principle of Epistemological Co-ordination in N.O. Losski&#8217;s Theory of Knowledge; Psycho-Politics and Mental Health Propaganda; Segregation Predates . History; Shall We Continue Latin And Greek In Our Schools&#8217;; Should We Undertake Systems Today?; Signs, Symbols, And Vagueness In Language; Summary of a Conversation with Chancellor Carmichael with Professor Donald Davidson, February 4, 1942; Summary of the Kritik of Pure Reason; There Are No Values or Value-Noun of Verb. Or On Pulling A Cat&#8217;s Tail; To The Intellectual Fighters of Paris and Vienna; "What Others Think"; William Stern&#8217;s Theory Of Personalism and Lasski&#8217;s Theory Of Concrete Ideal-Realism; Winter; A Workshop For Philosophers of The American Academy of Philosophy.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">27</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Newspapers</title>, <title render="underline">Newspaper</title> <title render="underline">Clippings</title> There are approximately, 300 newspaper clippings, and 8 newspapers. Newspapers are alphabetically arranged by title: <title render="underline">Common</title> <title render="underline">Sense</title>; <title render="underline">Free</title> <title render="underline">Enterprise</title>; <title render="underline">Free</title> <title render="underline">Men</title> <title render="underline">Speak</title>; <title render="underline">Industrial</title> <title render="underline">Weekly</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Manchester</title> <title render="underline">Guardian</title> <title render="underline">Weekly</title>; <title render="underline">Militant</title> <title render="underline">Truth</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">National</title> <title render="underline">Flouridation</title> <title render="underline">News</title>; <title render="underline">West</title> <title render="underline">Nashville</title> <title render="underline">News</title>.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">27-29</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Magazines</title>, <title render="underline">Magazine</title> <title render="underline">Clippings</title>. Material consists of approximately 100 magazine clippings and 74 magazines, alphabetically arranged by title: <title render="underline">Alpine</title> <title render="underline">Pastures</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">American</title> <title render="underline">Dachshund</title>; <title render="underline">American</title> <title render="underline">Daily</title> <title render="underline">Goat</title> <title render="underline">News</title>; <title render="underline">American</title> <title render="underline">fencing</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">American</title> <title render="underline">Nationalist</title>; <title render="underline">Another</title> <title render="underline">Language</title>; <title render="underline">Behavior</title> <title render="underline">Monographs</title>; <title render="underline">Beilage</title> <title render="underline">der</title> <title render="underline">Munchner</title> <title render="underline">Neuesten</title> <title render="underline">Nachrichten</title>; <title render="underline">Boston</title> <title render="underline">University</title> <title render="underline">Bulletin</title>; <title render="underline">Bulletin</title> <title render="underline">of</title> <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Dairy</title> <title render="underline">Research</title> <title render="underline">Bureau</title>; <title render="underline">Bulletin</title> <title render="underline">of</title> <title render="underline">Vanderbilt</title> <title render="underline">Univeristy</title>; <title render="underline">Challenge</title> <title render="underline">To</title> <title render="underline">Socialism</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Christian</title> <title render="underline">Century</title>; <title render="underline">Congressional</title> <title render="underline">Record</title>; <title render="underline">Dachs</title> <title render="underline">and</title> <title render="underline">Dashes</title>; <title render="underline">Der</title> <title render="underline">Dachshund</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Dashshund</title> <title render="underline">Club</title> <title render="underline">of</title> <title render="underline">America</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Dachshund</title> <title render="underline">Digest</title>; <title render="underline">Dachshund</title> <title render="underline">Diggings</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Defenders</title>&#8217; <title render="underline">News</title> <title render="underline">and</title> <title render="underline">Views</title>; <title render="underline">Economic</title> <title render="underline">Liberty</title>; <title render="underline">Ethical</title> <title render="underline">Culture</title> <title render="underline">Today</title>; <title render="underline">Freedom</title> <title render="underline">Facts</title>; <title render="underline">Gaines</title> <title render="underline">Dog</title> <title render="underline">Research</title> <title render="underline">Progress</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Greater</title> <title render="underline">Nebraskan</title>; <title render="underline">Headlines</title> <title render="underline">And</title> <title render="underline">What</title>&#8217;s <title render="underline">Behind</title> <title render="underline">Then</title>; <title render="underline">Hunan</title> <title render="underline">Events</title>; <title render="underline">Humanities</title> <title render="underline">in</title> <title render="underline">the</title> <title render="underline">South</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Journal</title> <title render="underline">of</title> <title render="underline">Philosophy</title>; <title render="underline">Kansas</title> <title render="underline">Dairy</title> <title render="underline">Goat</title> <title render="underline">Society</title> <title render="underline">Gazette</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Kennel</title> <title render="underline">News</title> <title render="underline">Bulletin</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Key</title> <title render="underline">Reporter</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Last</title> <title render="underline">Word</title> <title render="underline">in</title> <title render="underline">Kennel</title> <title render="underline">Science</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Liberty</title> <title render="underline">Bell</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Manion</title> <title render="underline">Forun</title>; <title render="underline">Modern</title> <title render="underline">Dogs</title>; <title render="underline">Monatshefte</title> <title render="underline">fur</title> <title render="underline">deutshce</title> <title render="underline">Sprache</title> <title render="underline">und</title> <title render="underline">Padagogik</title>; <title render="underline">Monographs</title> <title render="underline">Of</title> <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Society</title> <title render="underline">For</title> <title render="underline">Research</title> <title render="underline">In</title> <title render="underline">Child</title> <title render="underline">Development</title>; <title render="underline">National</title> <title render="underline">Defender</title>; <title render="underline">National</title> <title render="underline">Miniature</title> <title render="underline">Dachshund</title> <title render="underline">Club</title> <title render="underline">News</title>; <title render="underline">National</title> <title render="underline">Renaissance</title> <title render="underline">Bulletin</title>; <title render="underline">Nationalist</title>; <title render="underline">Party</title> <title render="underline">Bulletin</title>; <title render="underline">Natural</title> <title render="underline">Food</title> <title render="underline">And</title> <title render="underline">Farming</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">News</title>; <title render="underline">News</title> <title render="underline">and</title> <title render="underline">Hews</title>; <title render="underline">Newsweek</title>; <title render="underline">Northern</title> <title render="underline">World</title>; <title render="underline">Orange</title> <title render="underline">Peelings</title>; <title render="underline">Perceptual</title> <title render="underline">And</title> <title render="underline">Motor</title> <title render="underline">Skills</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Personalist</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Phi</title> <title render="underline">Betta</title> <title render="underline">Kappa</title> <title render="underline">Key</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Philosophical</title> <title render="underline">Review</title>; <title render="underline">Psychological</title> <title render="underline">Abstracts</title>; <title render="underline">Reconstructionist</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Reformation</title> <title render="underline">Review</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Revere</title>; <title render="underline">Right</title>; <title render="underline">School</title> <title render="underline">And</title> <title render="underline">Society</title>; <title render="underline">Scentific</title> <title render="underline">Monthly</title> <title render="underline">South</title> <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">News</title> <title render="underline">Magazine</title> <title render="underline">of</title> <title render="underline">Dixie</title>; <title render="underline">South</title> <title render="underline">Atlantic</title> <title render="underline">Bulletin</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Southern</title> <title render="underline">Philosophies</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Southern</title> <title render="underline">Society</title> <title render="underline">for</title> <title render="underline">Philosophy</title> <title render="underline">And</title> <title render="underline">Psychology</title>; <title render="underline">Southern</title> <title render="underline">States</title> <title render="underline">Industrial</title> <title render="underline">Council</title> <title render="underline">Bulletin</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Standard</title>; <title render="underline">Task</title> <title render="underline">Force</title>; <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Thunderbolt</title>; <title render="underline">Time</title> <title render="underline">The</title> <title render="underline">Weekly</title> <title render="underline">News</title> <title render="underline">Magazine</title>; <title render="underline">Tufts</title> <title render="underline">Alumni</title> <title render="underline">Review</title>; <title render="underline">U</title>.S.A. <title render="underline">An</title> <title render="underline">American</title> <title render="underline">Bulletin</title> <title render="underline">of</title> <title render="underline">Fact</title> <title render="underline">and</title> <title render="underline">Opinion</title>; <title render="underline">Williams</title> <title render="underline">Intelligence</title> <title render="underline">Summary</title>; <title render="underline">Women</title>&#8217;s <title render="underline">Voice</title>.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">29</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Pedigree</title> <title render="underline">Papers</title>. Material includes approximately 250 pedigree papers for dogs and goats. Also included are several applications for litter registtation and for transfer of ownership. certificates of health; and certificates of stud service.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">30</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Miscellaneous</title> <title render="underline">Writings</title>. Material consists of approximately 500 typescript pages. There are committee reports; annual reports; speeches and statements; constitutions and by-laws of various organizations; biographical sketches; minutes of meetings; and transcripts of court proceedings.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">30-31</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Photographs</title>. Appromimately 200 photographs of dogs, goats, people, and buildings.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">31</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Programs</title>. There are 51 programs of philosophical meetings, musical and theatrical performances, religious services, and dog shows, chronologically arranged from 1921 to 1960.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">31-32</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Advertisements</title>. Material includes approximately 300 advertisements for books, plants, foods, animal products, and tourist attractions.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">32-34</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Pamphlets, Flyers</title>. There are approximately 600 pamphlets and flyers dealing with a wide variety of subjects, from segregation to communism to dachshunds.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">34-36</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Phonograph</title> <title render="underline">Records</title>. There are 62 records, 61 of which contain bird songs. There is also a recording of a speech by Chancellor J.H. Kirkland.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">37</container>
<unittitle><title render="underline">Miscellaneous</title>. Approximately 250 items, including certificates awarded to Sanborn; various order forms and application-forms; un-used post cards and greeting cards; membership cards; calling cards; chain letters; a dog tag of Wiley M. Joyner, and a drawing of the Sanborn Family&#8217;s coat of arms.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>