<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
<eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
<eadid countrycode="US"></eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper type="filing">Buchanan, Margaret and Charles Collection</titleproper>
<titleproper>Finding Aid for the Margaret and Charles Buchanan Collection</titleproper>
<author></author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher>Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books</publisher>
<p><date>Undated</date></p>
<address>
<addressline>419 21st Avenue South</addressline>
<addressline>Nashville, TN 37203-2427</addressline>
<addressline>specialcollections@vanderbilt.edu</addressline>
<addressline>URL:
<extptr xlink:href="http://www.library.vanderbilt.edu/speccol/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.library.vanderbilt.edu/speccol/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
</address>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<langmaterial>
<language langcode="eng">English</language>
</langmaterial>
<repository>
<corpname>Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books</corpname>
</repository>
<unittitle>Margaret and Charles Buchanan Collection</unittitle>
<unitid>MSS.0060</unitid>
<physdesc altrender="whole">
<extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.42 linear feet</extent>
</physdesc>
<unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
</did>
<bioghist>
<head>Biographical Sketch</head>
<p><emph render="bold">Margaret Gwin Baskette</emph></p>
<p>The autograph album of Margaret Gwin Baskette was given to the Special Collections Department of the Joint University Libraries on April 11, 1968. The donor was Pearl Leigh Buchanan, a graduate of Peabody who received an M.A. in 1929 and who, at the time of the donation, was a Professor at Eastern Kentucky University. The autograph album belonged to &#8220;Maggie&#8221; as her friends called her. The V.U. <emph render="underline">Alumni Directory</emph> (May 1923) lists her years of matriculation as 1881-1883. She was embarking on a career in journalism and was publishing articles and stories in the Nashville <emph render="underline">Banner</emph>. Women were not admitted to Vanderbilt at that time, but she was given special permission to attend these classes. She became the wife of Charles Henry Buchanan, a ministerial student; they were married on October 21, 1885. They had one daughter, Pearl Leigh Buchanan. One of their classmates was Charles Soong of China (one of Soong&#8217;s daughters became Madame Sun Yat Sen and another became Madame Chiang Kai-Shek). Another classmate was John Orr, who became a librarian in the Congressional Library in Washington, D.C. Autographs of many other students are found in the album.</p>
<p><emph render="bold">Charles Henry Buchanan</emph></p>
<p>Charles Henry Buchanan (1858- ) attended the Vanderbilt Academic School and Biblical School from 1881 through 1884. He was a minister of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South, first spending 20 years as a pastor in Choteau, Oklahoma and subsequent years as a pastor in Central Texas and Baltimore, Maryland.</p>
<p>Rev. Buchanan was the author of <emph render="underline">A Gospel for the New Age; being the reality of religion as Jesus taught it</emph>, published in 1925 and <emph render="underline">Wanted: The Old Puritan Spirit as well</emph> as articles and editorials for the Texas <emph render="underline">Advocate</emph> and other church papers.</p>
<p>In 1882-1883, Rev. Buchanan helped organize and played on the first football team in Tennessee, made up of young Vanderbilt Academic and Biblical School students.</p>
<p>The Margaret and Charles Buchanan Collection include an autograph album, a bound copy of the <emph render="italic">Vanderbilt Observer</emph>, newspaper clippings, reminiscences and various ephemera. The Collection consists of one Hollinger box (.417 linear feet).</p>
</bioghist>
<dsc type="othertype">
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>A typescript letter to Margaret Buchanan, dated June 19, 1942, signed with an illegible signature by the Secretary to Dr. T.V. Soong, Minister for Foreign Affairs, Republic of China.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>1 Autograph album of Margaret Gwin Baskette which contains autographs collected while she was a student at Vanderbilt University, 1880-1883.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>1 Bound copy of the <emph render="underline">Vanderbilt Observer</emph>, dating from February, 1883 to June 1886, in which an index to the writings of Charles H. Buchanan is included.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>4 Newspaper clippings, 3 relate to Madame Chiang Kai-Shek, the other clipping is an untitled, anonymous poem.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>1 Reprint from the Vanderbilt Alumnus for February, 1932, titled &#8220;The Burning of Wesley Hall.&#8221;</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>1 Commencement Announcement for 1882.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>1 p. of reminiscences of the first football game organized and played in Tennessee.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
<c01 level="item">
<did>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>3 completed, handwritten questionnaires for V.U. <emph render="underline">Alumni Directory</emph>, 1925. Two are from Charles Henry Buchanan and one is from Margaret Buchanan.</unittitle>
</did>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
